<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Just For Fun</title><link href="/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>/</id><updated>2020-01-19T00:00:00-08:00</updated><entry><title>NINE THINGS TO DO TO FEEL BETTER ABOUT YOURSELF</title><link href="/nine-things-to-do-to-feel-better-about-yourself.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-01-19T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2020-01-19T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>EDIE YE</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-01-19:/nine-things-to-do-to-feel-better-about-yourself.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Lately, I have been researching about mental health and the problems that can arise from individuals with cognitive imbalances in the brain. This, in turn, made me think of what I personally do after being placed in a stressful situation. If you want to read more on why life is …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Lately, I have been researching about mental health and the problems that can arise from individuals with cognitive imbalances in the brain. This, in turn, made me think of what I personally do after being placed in a stressful situation. If you want to read more on why life is worth living, you can read more &lt;a href="https://edieye.ca/why-you-should-go-on.html"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;FOCUS ON THE MOMENT&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stop—stop for a moment and try to focus entirely on a random object. For example, in front of my desk is an orange. Some questions that quickly arise are—&lt;em&gt;where did this orange come from?&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;how many hands have touched it?&lt;/em&gt;, or &lt;em&gt;was the orange fruit named after the colour?&lt;/em&gt; The answers to the questions themselves can remain a mystery but at that moment in time, I am directing my focus entirely on the orange and nothing else. As ridiculous as what you read might sound, it works simply because the orange acts as a bridge between life being complicated and life being as simple as that, an orange. Try it on something, &lt;em&gt;on anything.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;CLEAN&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clean. Clean the dishes. Clean your room and the entire house if you have to. I know, cleaning is boring and requires physical work—but think about how you will feel after you are finished. Think about how accomplished you will feel from such a simple activity. Who knows, maybe you’ll find money or an old belonging that brings back some good, old memories. If that isn’t enough, think about how a clean house will feel—an organized room, folded clothes, dust-free laptop and tables—&lt;em&gt;it’s uplifting.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;EXERCISE&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Run. Go outside of your safe space and just run as fast as you can. This will get your endorphins going which will result in happiness. Run until you are out of breath. Walk it off and repeat until you can’t run anymore. You feel yourself gasping for air? &lt;em&gt;That is what it means to be alive.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;TAKE A SHOWER&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shower. Not only is the shower a perfect place to sing your favourite songs out of tune but a place to reflect and feel sorry for yourself as well. Have a long, hot shower and cry your heart out if needed. Sit on the ground and let the hot water clean every inch of your body. Let the steam soak into your skin and just focus on breathing. That said, promise yourself that the moment you turn off the water, you will move on from whatever troubles you felt. Leave the shower with a clean slate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;WRITE&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Write on paper—with a pen—I don’t necessarily mean words. Let whatever is on your mind, whatever emotion or problem translate to the paper in front of you. Scribble furiously or draw a picture of &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Toby_Flenderson"&gt;Toby&lt;/a&gt; if you have to. Write anything and have it not make sense to anyone but &lt;strong&gt;yourself&lt;/strong&gt;. When you are done, rip the paper into tens, hundreds of pieces and watch as they fall to the floor—the paper is your enemy. Sometimes having destructive thoughts can make you feel good. Don’t carry it out for too long though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;DRINK TEA&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Boil some water and make some tea. There are so many health benefits that come with tea—I will leave this to the experts. Watch as the tea leaves disperse and change the colour of the water. Realize that watching colours change is a simple experience that we often overlook. Sit on a chair with the teacup in your hands and wait patiently for the tea to cool. Feel the warmth in your stomach as you slowly sip the tea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;BECOME THE PERSON YOU WOULD FALL IN LOVE WITH&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go outside and open doors for strangers. Smile as they walk past you. Go for a drive and let cars merge into your lane. Pay for an extra parking ticket and leave the second one in the machine. Compliment people on their clothes. Compliment them on their personality. Ask people about their day or story even. Talk to acquaintances and try not to interrupt. Become friends with them, even if there are language barriers, age gaps, or cultural differences. When you see someone struggling, act selflessly to help them. Maybe it will take the weight off of your shoulders—who knows?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;WRITE DOWN A LIST OF GOALS&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Write down a list of goals to achieve for the day or week. Start with easy tasks such as waking up, brushing your teeth, drinking water, or going for a walk. Tick them off as you finish them. Being organized in such a manner teaches you that every small task can be seen as an accomplishment, as a &lt;a href="https://edieye.ca/what-does-success-look-like.html"&gt;success&lt;/a&gt;. Not only will you feel as you are doing more than usual, which will pep your mood (woohoo), but it will teach you to take on a more structured approach to planning things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;TAKE A BREAK FROM THE INTERNET&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take a break. You can do it. Do you know how many meaningless little things you trouble yourself with? These platforms—Email, Twitter, Snapchat, Instagram, Quora, Tumblr, LinkedIn, Facebook—you can take a break from them for a few minutes. For a day even. Don’t get me wrong, these socials have changed our lives for the better but when you become so enamoured with them that you can’t take a small break for yourself, it can become tiring. &lt;em&gt;Very tiring.&lt;/em&gt; Make some time for yourself—just yourself.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category><category term="pelican"></category><category term="mental health"></category><category term="self healing"></category><category term="self love"></category><category term="better"></category></entry><entry><title>WHAT IS THE MEANING OF LIFE</title><link href="/what-is-the-meaning-of-life.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-01-17T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2020-01-17T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>EDIE YE</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-01-17:/what-is-the-meaning-of-life.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have compiled a list of the two types of questions that are humanly impossible to answer, with one being &lt;a href="https://www.cut-the-knot.org/WhatIs/WhatIsAnalyticGeometry.shtml"&gt;analytic geometry&lt;/a&gt; in the third dimension (haha math is tough) and the other being questions of this form. That said, since you are already here, let me answer the impossible …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have compiled a list of the two types of questions that are humanly impossible to answer, with one being &lt;a href="https://www.cut-the-knot.org/WhatIs/WhatIsAnalyticGeometry.shtml"&gt;analytic geometry&lt;/a&gt; in the third dimension (haha math is tough) and the other being questions of this form. That said, since you are already here, let me answer the impossible to the best of my ability. Let me first ask you a few sub-questions—&lt;strong&gt;what&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;where&lt;/strong&gt; are we in the &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cosmos"&gt;cosmos&lt;/a&gt;?, &lt;strong&gt;why&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;how&lt;/strong&gt; does gravity prevent us from spinning off into space?, &lt;strong&gt;who&lt;/strong&gt; created the first form of life?, &lt;strong&gt;if&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;when&lt;/strong&gt; will time one day pass in reverse?, and &lt;strong&gt;what&lt;/strong&gt; are the ultimate limits to humans can know?
These questions, similar to the meaning of life, are difficult to answer yet have beauty because they are of the unknown. That said, maybe the meaning of life is simply, here and now. Maybe the journey—the struggling, the frustration, the hard work, and the tears themselves is the point. Maybe don't be so focused on searching for the meaning of life when the meaning of life is to give it meaning. Maybe, just maybe, the point is to avoid controlling things and just, well, &lt;em&gt;live&lt;/em&gt;. As &lt;a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt1065073/characters/nm3878243"&gt;Nicole&lt;/a&gt; would say, “You know how everyone’s always saying seize the moment? I don’t know, I’m kinda thinking its the other way around. You know, like the moment seizes us.”&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category><category term="pelican"></category><category term="life"></category><category term="meaning"></category><category term="cosmos"></category><category term="gravity"></category><category term="moment"></category></entry><entry><title>WHAT DOES SUCCESS LOOK LIKE</title><link href="/what-does-success-look-like.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-01-13T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2020-01-13T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>EDIE YE</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-01-13:/what-does-success-look-like.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The question “What makes one successful in life?” can usually be answered with a tangible good (e.g. money) or an abstract thought (e.g. power). That said, a fundamental problem to such answers is the possible controversy that can arise. The reason being is that success tends to fall …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The question “What makes one successful in life?” can usually be answered with a tangible good (e.g. money) or an abstract thought (e.g. power). That said, a fundamental problem to such answers is the possible controversy that can arise. The reason being is that success tends to fall in the hands of the beholder, meaning that there is no universal truth to success that is shared amongst everyone. The sub-questions that then follow are “How do you measure success?” or even more simply, “What is the definition of success?” The &lt;a href="https://www.dictionary.com/browse/webster-s-dictionary"&gt;Webster Dictionary&lt;/a&gt; defines
&lt;a href="https://www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary/success"&gt;success&lt;/a&gt; as “the fact of getting or achieving, wealth, respect or fame” which again, can be the definition for some people or the majority even, but that definition is not universal. At different points in life, the definitions and or measurements of success change. For this reason, I will write more on what intrinsic traits a successful person possesses rather than trying to draw a picture of a successful person. Although I am by no means at the stage where I can label myself as successful per se, I will delve into this topic further by sharing some of my successful experiences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the earliest memories I have of my childhood takes me back to my first days or week of preschool. I, for whatever reason, was riddled with separation anxiety from my grandpa, who at the time, was not only my guardian, but my best friend as well. It was honestly a strange concept because I remembered each child that was dropped off by a family member or guardian, and their ability to immediately interact with children and toys around them after being dropped off. Anyways, my grandpa had to remain with me while I interacted with the other kids and I remember every time he made a futile attempt to sneak away, I would cry almost immediately. The whole process of me getting comfortable with everyone took around a week and, if I remember correctly, it wasn’t until that period was over that I was able to be without the presence of my grandpa. While this may be seen as an embarrassment to others or a questionable experience even, it was my first memorable taste of victory and success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;BE PATIENT&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In hindsight, there are a number of general accomplishments that happen in our lives whether we realize this or not, not limited to but including learning to walk, to read, or even to use the toilet. While these events have transpired quite a period of time ago, it is important to recognize the amount of time and energy that went into being successful with these tasks. This brings me to the first attribute of being successful—learning to &lt;strong&gt;be patient.&lt;/strong&gt; As cliche as it sounds, success is not something that happens over night. I say this because as a child, I believe that one of the traits many of us shared was not giving up easily and having the courage to attempt new activities, hence being able to effectively learn to verbally communicate, socially interact with others, etc. Speaking entirely for myself, I realized as I grew older, I saw a shift in how much quicker I would need to see results before deeming activities as worth the time. I saw while I was learning to be more patient with others, how impatient I was when it came to myself. The reason behind this is as I grew older, I learned more about myself. When I say learning more about myself, I mean understanding my goals, aspirations, likes, and dislikes. I mean having expectations for myself, which I hold to the highest standard. While it is so, so important to have goals and aspirations, this is a reminder to myself and everyone to be patient with not only the people around them but with themselves as well because success will come with time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;BE RESPECTFUL&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was fifteen, I took on my first job at the &lt;a href="https://www.pne.ca/"&gt;PNE&lt;/a&gt; as a sweeper and this has been rewarding in every aspect. It was not the job duties itself that was monumental nor was there a life changing event that took my breath away. However, it taught me about the value of money (because your sweat translating to your first pay cheque is a woohoo moment), about consistency, and most importantly, about hard work. I then went on to pick up other work prior to the beginning of my software development career, including serving in a restaurant, working in retail, working in concession stands, and even working as a manager in my high school store. If you want to read more about where I interned or where I am currently working you can read more &lt;a href="edieye.ca/about"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Needless to say, I would love to go into detail about each of my work experiences, but it would stray too far from the point I am trying to establish—learning to treat everyone you meet with respect and as an opportunity to learn. &lt;strong&gt;Being respectful&lt;/strong&gt; is of great value and realizing that every person you meet can teach you something will never, ever hinder your growth. This is because the people you meet can teach you what to be and what not to be. I believe, every now and then, quite unintentionally, someone teaches you something about yourself. I say this because I remember serving at a restaurant and witnessing dishwashers being treated poorly by some servers. I remember there was a basket which was intended for the server to put their dirty dishes in. Some servers, out of laziness, would toss dishes that still had food remains into the said basket and remains or sauces would deflect back onto the dishwashers’ clothes or face, even. Of course, this was of the rarest occasions and, of course, the servers apologized but there was, without a doubt, a blatant disregard for the dishwasher. Had it been someone of a deemed, valuable position, I doubt the dishes would have been carelessly tossed into the basket. Yes, I am elucidating the impression that some people are condescending and mistreat others and yes, I am asking you to not behave in this manner because not only is it a backwards movement, but it hinders growth. It is beneficial to recognize the value of every person you meet and every experience that takes place because growth comes from reflection, and not from exuding negativity towards others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;BE CONFIDENT&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last trait I want to talk about is one I struggled with for a good period of time—&lt;strong&gt;being confident.&lt;/strong&gt; I say this to the people that don’t believe they have what it takes to take themselves to the level they aspire to be to find the courage to do so. My prior anecdote about my preschool experience is a translation for the parts of my life where I honestly felt uncomfortable being under my own skin. Truth is, you have to put yourself in uncomfortable situations because these situations will eventually become comfortable to you. For example, take a look at typing with a keyboard. At one point in our lives, we probably used two index fingers and had trouble typing a complete sentence without looking up at the screen. After finishing the sentence, being slightly smug about it, and then looking at our screen again, we probably realized that we had mistyped. &lt;em&gt;How uncomfortable.&lt;/em&gt; I understand that for some people, even getting out of bed and having basic conversation with others can be exhausting, but recognize that as long as you take baby steps to work on being comfortable with the uncomfortable, the confidence will eventually come! With that said, it is also important to recognize the difference between being arrogant and confident. As &lt;a href="https://theoffice.fandom.com/wiki/Vikram"&gt;Vikram&lt;/a&gt; would say, “confidence, it’s the food of the wise man, but the liquor of the fool.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many traits that can help lead one to success but those are the three I am trying to work on in the coming year and I know how cliche these traits are made out to be. Truth is, everything in life is cliche. The idea that you are very different from someone else is only true if you consider a &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Decision_tree"&gt;decision tree&lt;/a&gt;, where each step or decision would alter the course of life. However, these branches very often intersect and lead to a similar path. Even the idea that you think you are different is not much different than the other millions of people that have shared this thought , and with that said, I truly believe anyone can feel or be successful regardless of how many bad branches that stemmed from their tree. I have digressed again but I believe success is intrinsic and can not be answered with some social status or some physical good. Success is ultimately looking in the mirror and liking what you see.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category><category term="pelican"></category><category term="self"></category><category term="patience"></category><category term="memory"></category><category term="success"></category><category term="life"></category><category term="confidence"></category></entry><entry><title>WHY YOU SHOULD GO ON</title><link href="/why-you-should-go-on.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-01-09T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2020-01-09T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>EDIE YE</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-01-09:/why-you-should-go-on.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;One of the saddest messages I received recently was that one of my childhood friends was at the tipping point of depression. I am dedicating this post wholeheartedly to you and to everyone else who feels that their world is moments from crumbling down. This is a reminder that sometimes …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;One of the saddest messages I received recently was that one of my childhood friends was at the tipping point of depression. I am dedicating this post wholeheartedly to you and to everyone else who feels that their world is moments from crumbling down. This is a reminder that sometimes, there are events that take place which we have absolutely no control over. We do have a choice though, which is either to give up or to &lt;strong&gt;keep on fighting,&lt;/strong&gt; and I hope your choice is to keep on fighting. &lt;em&gt;Every damn time.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me begin by saying I am no expert in human psychology nor do I know how to take methodical approaches with conversation to better understand victims with depression. With that in mind, these are the aspects of life that I personally think are worth living for, and in turn, the reasons you need to keep &lt;strong&gt;fighting.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;LIVE FOR FAMILY&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You need to live for your family, whether it is your parents, siblings, pets, or friends who have become family. I believe the term family goes hand in hand with home, so when I think of family, I tend to think of things that make me feel at &lt;strong&gt;home.&lt;/strong&gt; These things could be, well, anything that makes you feel at peace. It could be a thought, a place, or even a person, because home is as simple as that. It is but a feeling, a thought. Some people can argue that they have no home or that they are difficult to love, but that is silly. Look harder. Look smarter. One of the greatest gifts that humans have been blessed with is the ability to make foreign places and people their home. There must be a moment, a thought, or a memory that triggers a flux in serotonin which you can hold onto with your dear life. Personally, when I think about home, the first thought that comes to mind are my parents who immigrated to Canada and sacrificed their passions and career for me to chase mine. Every time I encounter hardships, I am reminded of how disappointed my parents would be if I decided to give up on myself, when they have yet to give up on me. The inexplicable, unconditional parental love truly has me at a loss for words, but its complexity is something I will perpetually cherish. By the way mom, if you ever stumble upon and read this, this in no way implies that I am willing to do the dishes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;LIVE FOR SUNSETS AND SUNRISES&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You need to live for sunsets and sunrises. Do I need to say more? The fleeting beauty of sunsets and sunrises never fail to take me away from my perceived troubles. There is something extremely peaceful about commodities that humans have no control over. Humans have a strange tendency to want to control things, to plan things, and I am no exception. However, when I have the opportunity to slip away from the working world and focus entirely on the elapsing beauty of the sun being swallowed away by the clouds, I am reminded again of the endless possibilities of life. It is empowering to think, when you look at the sun, that there are no apparent social hierarchies or arcane policies of monarchy. This is because the feelings that evoke and the experiences that form are completely and &lt;strong&gt;utterly yours.&lt;/strong&gt; In those moments, you need to realize that even the darkest nights will soon burn bright again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;LIVE FOR FIRST EXPERIENCES&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You need to live for first time experiences. There are so many first times and the few that quickly come to my mind are graduating from high school, graduating from college, riding a bike, driving a car, and flying in an airplane. Every time I reflect on a first time experience, I am reminded of my stomach churning with excitement. I am reminded of the flood in emotions of both nervousness and eagerness, and it never fails to leave me in anticipation for what is yet to come. Say we compare your life to a book. The chapters would be a metaphor for each new experience, the pages for the days, and the lines for the emotions you felt and or actions of that day. It is then important to recognize that you need to read every line in the book, regardless of how you currently feel about the story. Of course, you can be sad, frustrated, or angry even but please know that a new chapter will eventually begin and the only way to know what the upcoming chapters entail is to &lt;strong&gt;keep reading.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;LIVE FOR YOURSELF&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You need to live for yourself. Live for the good. Live for the small moments that take your breath away. Live for the small moments that you have with yourself. Live because that is what it means to be alive. Live for yourself because you &lt;em&gt;can.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category><category term="self-love"></category><category term="appreciation"></category><category term="family"></category><category term="first-experience"></category></entry><entry><title>WHY I STARTED WRITING</title><link href="/why-i-started-writing.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-12-02T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2019-12-02T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>EDIE YE</name></author><id>tag:None,2019-12-02:/why-i-started-writing.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;When asked why I decided to write, my knee jerk response would be why not? However, the analytical side of me wants to explore the not-so-bright part of my brain that is actively encouraging me to document part of my, very much, mundane life.  For the people reading that don …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;When asked why I decided to write, my knee jerk response would be why not? However, the analytical side of me wants to explore the not-so-bright part of my brain that is actively encouraging me to document part of my, very much, mundane life.  For the people reading that don’t know me very well or just happened to stumble on this page, I want to apologize in advance for the plethora of &lt;a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt0386676/"&gt;The Office&lt;/a&gt; references which is what I am fundamentally built on, as one of my friends would put it. To add to this, the focus of my posts are not for motivation, so if you are reading this with the intent of finding some sort of light to drive you or the means to fill an existing void, then you are probably looking in the wrong place. With that in mind, hopefully, you do find my experiences insightful and worth the read. My posts will largely be personal and I hope to share all my experiences, for regardless of whether they  were blessings or valuable experiences that did not immediately present themselves, they helped to shape me as an individual. Lastly, I want my blog to act as an unconfined space on the Internet where I can freely write about, well, anything that comes to mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us start with a brief biography about myself; I am a Bachelors of Science graduate from the University of British Columbia with a focus in computer science and am based in Vancouver, Canada. I am an avid hiker during the summer and watch The Office religiously, hence the occasional references. Another point that I can share about myself is that I was fortunate enough to be able to find an area of study (i.e. computer science) which I thoroughly enjoy. That being said, it honestly wasn’t a clear path to begin with and even when I decided with computer science, there were quite a few hurdles to overcome. I will probably expand further on the ins and outs of the reasons I decided to partake in my software development journey in a post or a portion of a post to come.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The result of me pursuing computer science has resulted in me to take on a more structured approach to thinking about problems and while this has been rewarding in many aspects, one of the spaces I no longer found myself in was creative writing. This is not to say that programming lacks a creative side, as there are multiple solutions to a single problem and many developers tackle problems in a different manner. However, I missed the freedom of having my mind sporadically run off on a tangent. In other words, I wasn’t able to find the type of freedom in my everyday activities that creative writing allows for. While structured approaches and logic are great for reasoning and explaining problems as one can map out points from A to B and from B to C, I believe there is a creative outlet in writing that can’t be tapped from logic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another reason I decided to write after much consideration is that I wanted to leave a digital footprint that I can look back on when feeling nostalgic. One of the cruel realities of life is not being wired to remember all the highlights of our lives. While technologies such as the camera or video recorder have given us the ability to capture these moments in real time, there are periods in our lives where it would be inappropriate to use such technologies (e.g. movie theater). Moreover, I believe that even when the moments are appropriate to capture through technology, writing can simply act as an extension to these captured memories. Writing allows for the time to collect thoughts and emotions to reflect on specific moments in time. Lastly, I once was a firm believer in not capturing moments with photos or videos as I didn’t think you were seizing the moment with the presence of your phone. Nonetheless, after realizing that our brains are not structured to remember every immaculate detail of an experience, it makes logical sense to capture at least part of the experience prior to putting the technologies away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea of primal instinct suggests that humans, as a species, are motivated by self-preservation and survival which complies with &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Darwinism"&gt;Darwin’s Theory of Evolution&lt;/a&gt;. The reason I bring this up is that I believe that it is an instinct to want to protect yourself, an instinct to want to be cherished, and an instinct to want to compete. To accentuate my point, when we look at &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural_selection"&gt;natural selection&lt;/a&gt;, we can see there are many animals with cannibalistic tendencies and this can be seen as basic competition. Now, fortunately for us, the majority of animals and humans in contemporary society have evolved to not compete to this extent as somewhere along the way, we learned about compassion. Having said all that, I do believe that humans, when pushed to extremes, can and will release their buried anger in forms of hostility. This is why we have hobbies, loved ones, and other forms of stress relievers to suppress this innate behavior. I know I did run off on a tangent there, but I guess what I want to say is one of the reasons for the creation of this blog is to allow my mind to wander and release the stresses that come with ordinary, everyday living. I hope that answers why I am writing and if it still doesn’t, my response would again be, why not?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you for reading about a very ordinary post from my very ordinary life. Feel free to leave suggestions for what topics you want me to cover or things I could improve on as any constructive feedback would be greatly appreciated. Hopefully this post urges you to find a passion or hobby that takes away the stresses of everyday living and helps you to realize that it is quite alright to be ordinary. As &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pam_Beesly"&gt;Pam&lt;/a&gt; would say, “there’s a lot of beauty in ordinary things. Isn’t that the point?”&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category><category term="pelican"></category><category term="publishing"></category><category term="self"></category><category term="blog"></category></entry></feed>