<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Just For Fun</title><link href="/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>/</id><updated>2021-11-12T00:00:00-08:00</updated><entry><title>On Problems</title><link href="/2021/11/on-problems/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-11-12T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2021-11-12T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>EDIE YE</name></author><id>tag:None,2021-11-12:/2021/11/on-problems/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;You know what sucks?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Problems, those suck.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even before you were born – nine months earlier – you could have already been a nascent problem. Perhaps, your parents weren’t excepting you. Perhaps it wasn’t the right time. Perhaps they were encumbered by their financial ability. Perhaps, they weren’t ready …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;You know what sucks?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Problems, those suck.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even before you were born – nine months earlier – you could have already been a nascent problem. Perhaps, your parents weren’t excepting you. Perhaps it wasn’t the right time. Perhaps they were encumbered by their financial ability. Perhaps, they weren’t ready. Perhaps, it was for a different reason altogether. Perhaps…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mean, it hurts right, to realize you could have been a burden to someone else even prior to developing in the womb? Well, it doesn’t get better because from the moment you leave the womb and deafen your parents and until the day of your last breath, you are a problem. Possibly, even thereafter.
Hence the funeral.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But maybe problems are good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is, you exist, right? you, a &lt;a href="https://www.wboc.com/story/43554205/the-chances-of-you-being-born-are-far-lower-than-you-think"&gt;one in four trillion fluke&lt;/a&gt;, exist. That, itself, is a miracle and should be celebrated as such. It should be celebrated because in an infinitely problematic world hosting an infinite number of problems, you just so happen to exist. Those are the odds and that is, with the given presuppositions, irrefutable.
When I was four, I was extremely attached to my grandpa. At the time, there was an inexplicable, phenomenal bond I shared with him that I’ve yet to and don’t plan to share with another individual. Looking back, it was probably because he coddled me; he was a yes-man, so whenever we passed by a grocery store and I asked, he would procure candy for me. He was an over-protective guardian, so whenever I had conflicts with my siblings and or cousins, he would take my side. He was, without a doubt, the ideal grandparent anyone could wish for at that age. He sheltered me from the cruel but very real outside world, and it was amazing. That is, until we had to separate for a period of time because of pre-school.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the first day he tried to drop me off, he couldn’t leave. He had to stand by the door and watch over me. I, despite being able to play with the toys and other children, would consistently glance over to ensure his presence. Whenever he futilely attempted to escape my vision, I would freeze and cry. I bawled my eyes dry that day. That said, I eventually learned to function without his companionship albeit it may have taken copious amounts of time. It was both a process and a compromise: I made him promise to stay a little longer before leaving and to arrive a little earlier to pick me up, and in turn, I wouldn’t make a scene. In time, I warmed up to the other kids and made friends even.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reflecting on this experience and me being embarrassed aside, what stood out for me was the introduction of a problem (i.e. me) via an over-cautious grandparent (i.e. him). In a way, he solved all my problems until I, myself, became the problem. By sheltering me, by coddling me, by leaving me to be invulnerable, he made me vulnerable. It’s &lt;a href="http://www.brooklyntherapist.net/blog/2018/6/12/alan-watts-backwards-law"&gt;Watt’s backwards law&lt;/a&gt; – the more you try to hold onto something, the more it slips through the crevices of your hand; the more you try to control a situation, the more it controls you; the more you try to avoid musing over a problem, the more you end up musing over it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, my grandpa isn’t to blame because how can I blame someone with pure and loving intentions? Furthermore, I wouldn’t alter the past, as with its multitudes of problems, it has also helped to mould my becoming. I like to believe that everyone has a set of problems starting at the physiological level and culminating at self-actualization. Maslow refers to these as needs but I refer to them as problems. I like to believe that life has myriad problems; whenever a problem is resolved, another takes its place. When you’re in pre-school, the problems are simpler – math puzzles, shapes matching, or in my case, separation anxiety. When you’re in school, the problems are replaced with making friends, fostering relationships, keeping up with your education and so forth. On this basis, I have an inkling that problems are on-going but with this inkling, I somehow feel more free. It’s Watt’s backwards law again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Under the premise that problems are on-going and perpetual, the one thing I ask of you is to experience things a little. Drink a gallon of water a day even if you have to pee every hour. Wake up at four am to hike for fourteen hours even if you know your legs are going to be sore the next day. Run an arduous marathon even if you can’t remember the last time running has crossed your mind. Read ten books in one sitting even if you haven’t picked up a book in ages. Fall asleep for a twenty-four hour duration even if you can’t remember the last time you’ve slept well. Call your grandparents and tell them you love them even if you haven’t connected in a while. I don’t know – just live a little because problems will continue to exist, and at times, feel insurmountable even.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So don’t try to live a life without a problems as that’s impossible. Rather, try to live a life with problems you find worth solving and have a little fun along the way, because thats’s what is meaningful. That’s what is going to feel good. And that’s what you’re going to remember.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="2021"></category><category term="problems"></category><category term="self"></category><category term="time"></category></entry><entry><title>I WANT TO BE EVERYTHING</title><link href="/2020/09/i-want-to-be-everything/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-09-27T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-09-27T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>EDIE YE</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-09-27:/2020/09/i-want-to-be-everything/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I want to be everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to learn about psychology – to understand why people are the way they are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to learn about construction – to design and develop my own home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to learn about philosophy –  to question the universe and the fundamental nature of our existence …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I want to be everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to learn about psychology – to understand why people are the way they are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to learn about construction – to design and develop my own home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to learn about philosophy –  to question the universe and the fundamental nature of our existence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to learn and be everything, but that's impossible. &lt;em&gt;Or so I've heard.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just kidding – that’s the reality. That said, there is this unshakeable part of me that is unwilling to give up on anything. Don't get me wrong, I give up on things. Everyone does, everyday. But it hasn't gotten easier and it probably never will.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea is this – when you make a choice or transaction, you give something up. The simplest transaction is exchanging a good for money (i.e. giving up money for said good). In an ideal world, you would keep both the money and good but that isn't possible in most scenarios, to say the least.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now take the same idea and extend it to every decision you've made in your life. In the beginning, there is infinite potential. You are free to be anything you want. As choices are made, the choices that follow become more and more narrow. But more and more significant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The college you attend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The field you major in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first internship or job you take.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The place you settle down in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The person you spend your life with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite having made some of those decisions and loving the choices I've made, I've come to the realization that there is much more that I want to learn and unwilling to give up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because I don't want to give anything up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I still want to be everything.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="2020"></category><category term="self"></category><category term="time"></category></entry><entry><title>TIME</title><link href="/2020/06/time/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-06-14T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-06-14T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>EDIE YE</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-06-14:/2020/06/time/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Time is linear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Time is linear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Time is linear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That sounds aggressive but time is linear and I keep treating it as if it's circular. What do I mean? Well, I very often &lt;em&gt;wait&lt;/em&gt; for things to be over and I very often &lt;em&gt;wait&lt;/em&gt; for things to happen because, in …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Time is linear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Time is linear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Time is linear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That sounds aggressive but time is linear and I keep treating it as if it's circular. What do I mean? Well, I very often &lt;em&gt;wait&lt;/em&gt; for things to be over and I very often &lt;em&gt;wait&lt;/em&gt; for things to happen because, in the back of my mind, I know a cycle repeats itself. But that's the problem though, because it doesn't - time doesn't repeat itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is much irony in time because we know it isn't promised yet we treat it as such. The reason could be that many of its attributes suggest a perpetual cycle. A minute is composed of sixty seconds, an hour of sixty minutes, a day of twenty-four hours, a week of seven days, and a year of fifty-two weeks. Every segment said above repeats itself and maybe that's the problem – we think we have time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below is an image where each square represents a week and each row a year. As there are ninety rows, this is your entire life if you live until ninety. Note: The image was taken from &lt;a href="https://waitbutwhy.com/2014/05/life-weeks.html"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;img alt="90-year-timeline" src="/2020/06/time/images/90-year-timeline.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This photo scares me. A lot. Suppose I crossed the boxes out as the weeks passed like a calendar – one big X for each week until the big day presents itself. Suppose I colour each box with either green or red – green for when the number of good days surpass the bad for that week, and red otherwise. In both scenarios, I am frightened because I never imagined life to have a deadline. I mean, I did, but not like this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That said, the photo gives me hope too. Because if I am to map / reduce my life to this chart, I want it to have a positive connotation. If I am to draw Xs', I want to draw each X with a smile. If I am to colour boxes, I want to have a plethora of green boxes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But if I want said results, it means I have to take control of my life. It means I have to take action instead of just dreaming. Because that's the thing – anyone can dream.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyone can dream to travel but it only happens when a ticket is booked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyone can dream to have a great body but it only happens with consistent exercise and a healthy diet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyone can dream to be wealthy but it only happens with discipline and hard work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So this post is a reminder to start now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Because those boxes are getting filled out either way.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="2020"></category><category term="life"></category><category term="time"></category></entry><entry><title>THE SIGNIFICANCE OF WORDS</title><link href="/2020/05/the-significance-of-words/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-05-13T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-05-13T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>EDIE YE</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-05-13:/2020/05/the-significance-of-words/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Or rather, the loss in significance of words. Words, in their simplest form, serve as a means for communication; however, seemingly social norms of contemporary society have disrupted its purpose – or at least to my knowledge. To clarify, etymology is not the focus of this piece; nor are words in …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Or rather, the loss in significance of words. Words, in their simplest form, serve as a means for communication; however, seemingly social norms of contemporary society have disrupted its purpose – or at least to my knowledge. To clarify, etymology is not the focus of this piece; nor are words in the domain of an average &lt;a href="https://www.urbandictionary.com/define.php?term=Zoomer"&gt;Zoomer&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Generation_Z"&gt;Gen Z&lt;/a&gt;er (e.g. &lt;a href="https://www.urbandictionary.com/define.php?term=woke"&gt;woke&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.dictionary.com/e/slang/yeet/"&gt;yeet&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.urbandictionary.com/define.php?term=No%20cap"&gt;no cap&lt;/a&gt;). The content focuses on common phrases that have disrupted the nature of communication – or rather, phrases that are ironic / have lost its meaning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Not to be, but…&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be impartial, I use this phrase a good amount and am trying to reduce its usage. Why? Well, to me, it acts as a strategy to prepare others for the words to come. After phrases such as: “not to be racist, but…”, “not to be mean, but…”,  or “not to be rude, but..”, the user has a tendency to be exactly that - racist, mean, or rude. As such, it seems that the phrase very often mentally prepares the conversation for whatever the individual actually intends to be; ironic, isn’t it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;I’m sorry you feel that way&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is anything but an apology – it’s a non-apology. Its implications are clear – the person on the receiving end &lt;em&gt;shouldn’t&lt;/em&gt; and are &lt;em&gt;wrong&lt;/em&gt; to feel a certain way. It not only lacks compassion and empathy, but is a means distance the conversation. While the phrase contains the word sorry, it entails the opposite. An apology supposedly acts as a regretful acknowledgment and if one apologizes with an attack mechanism, why apologize at all?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Frankly, ...&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The user will not be frank ninety-nine percent of the time and that comes with no surprise at all. Unless their name is Frank.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;That is amazing / awesome&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It baffles me how some people describe every situation as amazing or awesome. Not to be a negative Nancy but how is getting fast food for lunch awesome? In what way does it cause great surprise / wonder or is impressive / daunting? Perhaps if it was a first time experience and the taste was wonderful. But if you eat fast food every week and consider it awesome, it makes others question how awesome your life actually is. Not to take away the pleasure from eating fast food or performing routine tasks, but how do they compare to visiting the Great Wall? Or The Grand Canyon? It goes without saying that everyone has their definition of amazing / awesome and can apply it to situations of their choosing, but I find that the profuse use of certain words to take away from its meaning. Perhaps, when you have a truly awesome experience, you will find yourself at a loss for words; and wouldn't it be horrible if the reason was because you used them all up eating fast food?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not an exhaustive list and I carry no contempt for those that don’t say what they mean – it's hard. That said, I fail to see the point of communicating when words no longer carry significance. Why speak if our words do not reflect how we truly feel? Why make promises if we are not to deliver them? The greatest irony is when communication, which serves as a bridge to the unknown, obstructs itself through its own medium (i.e. words). If so, why speak at all?&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="2020"></category><category term="life"></category><category term="words"></category></entry><entry><title>MY FAVORITE WORD</title><link href="/2020/05/my-favorite-word/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-05-01T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-05-01T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>EDIE YE</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-05-01:/2020/05/my-favorite-word/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Balance. That is my favourite word. The term balance applies to a myriad of situations, and most ideas and activities, when thought about and done in balance, suggest a positive connotation. Living with balance – whether in passion, work, or relationships – is vital to the well-being of individuals. Without balance, our …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Balance. That is my favourite word. The term balance applies to a myriad of situations, and most ideas and activities, when thought about and done in balance, suggest a positive connotation. Living with balance – whether in passion, work, or relationships – is vital to the well-being of individuals. Without balance, our wants and needs can be compromised which, in turn, can affect our happiness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;WHERE PASSION FAILS&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Contemporary society — myself included — often views passion as a positive term, among other things. However, if we follow the etymology of passion, it stems from Latin word &lt;a href="https://owlcation.com/humanities/The-Etymology-of-Passion"&gt;patior&lt;/a&gt;, meaning to suffer. This directly corresponds to the all too familiar quote find what you love and let it kill you or to find what you love and suffer via your passion. Don’t get me wrong. Passion is not all bad. It demonstrates willpower and resilience. It, in the correct circumstances, can help with focus and growth too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To have a better understanding of passion, let us first explore the two major schools of thought in passion (i.e. harmonious and obsessive) as per &lt;a href="https://selfdeterminationtheory.org/SDT/documents/2003_VallerancBlanchardMageauKoesnterRatelleLeonardGagneMacolais_JPSP.pdf"&gt;Les Passions de l’Ame&lt;/a&gt;. According to Les Passions de l’Ame, obsessive passion is developed with contingencies attached to the activity such as feelings of social acceptance or self-esteem, or because the sense of excitement derived becomes uncontrollable (Vallerand et Al, 2003). Harmonious passion, on the other hand, is developed without contingencies (Vallerand et Al, 2003).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If or when passion manifests to a point where the time and energy invested leads to the constant negligence of mental and physical health, family, or friends, then that passion has become obsessive. Oftentimes, this passion is directly linked to a reward system –  money, promotion, fame, or social media followers even. When said passion blossoms, our mental image of self-worth becomes flawed because it is no longer the activity itself we value, but the opinions of others that fulfill us. This is directly linked to &lt;a href="https://www.psychologytoday.com/ca/basics/burnout"&gt;burning out&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The question that follows then is how to avoid obsessive passion and the answer would be to maintain balance or harmony. Cultivating harmonious passion does not result in burning out as it does not take you away from yourself. Rather, it acts as an extension to who you already are. Reason being is the engagement of the activity stems from simple love for the activity and not some metric or external validation. This is not to say you do not see metrics or external validation in harmonious passion, but these are not the driving factors behind it. When an activity is done with harmonious passion, walking away from said activity is possible if it has become toxic. As such, passion with balance is better than passion without.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;WHERE WORK FAILS&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Balance in work is important. Work stress is ubiquitous across all industries and work has or will take up a huge portion of your life. Fortunately for me, one of my passions (i.e. computer science) is incorporated into my work (i.e. software development). I do, however, know people who have chosen majors and careers from the influence of friends and family. As soon as they finish, they feel empty because they think &lt;em&gt;now what?&lt;/em&gt; Maybe they aren’t wrong to think that – I don’t know. What I do know is the importance of taking a balanced set of courses, rather than just those in your major.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The course(s) might not end up as a passion. But it might.  Either way, it’s worth trying. I mean, in my fourth year, I took my first gender studies course – the interdisciplinary exploration of multiple intersections between gender and (neo) colonialism, racism, poverty, ableism, and heterosexism in a globalized world. Although the material itself was interesting, I did not enjoy the course work as much as I thought I would. It did however, provide me with a much needed break from my software development work. So despite the material not being that of which I wanted to delve deeper into, it gave me a better clarification for what I enjoyed and did not enjoy. Therefore, for me, the course was worth taking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, so suppose you are lucky and find passion in your work. The next most common step is to hone applicable skills for that promotion. And the next step after that? Develop yourself even further for another promotion, probably. That is where the problem rises because climbing the corporate ladder comes with a price and sometimes, the trade-off is not worth its while.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To remain impartial, let me address both the positive and negatives. Some positives include a cushier lifestyle, more responsibilities and enjoyment in your work, and less worries about struggling financially to make ends meet. Some negatives include higher expenditure (if lifestyle changes are made), more stress (if more responsibilities are handled), and less personal time (if promotion requires longer hours). I could go on, but ultimately, if or when the investment into work changes too much of your pre-existing life too fast, problems can arise. So yeah, balance in work is pretty important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;WHERE RELATIONSHIPS FAIL&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me begin by saying that relationships are difficult. For me, even maintaining connections with friends is hard, let alone a significant other. As a result, my social circle has become smaller and smaller over the years. One of the reasons is a shift in personal interest – when I was younger I found myself coming home in the morning quite often. While most people were getting ready to start their day, I was ending mine. Now, I tend to sleep at 10:30 - 11:00 PM and wake up at 6:00 - 6:30 AM. Don’t get me wrong, I still enjoy a night out on occasion. But I prefer to be at home, in my bed, before the morning now. The second reason is that many of my friends have joined the workforce and some have moved cities even. As a result, it has become harder to keep up with everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that said, there seems to be an apparent pattern for maintaining friendships and relationships. The pattern is that nothing should be forced – that both parties have their share of push and pull. Let me share a story to attest to the veracity of that statement. There was a time in my life when I was eager to be in a relationship. Very eager. It started off great. I messaged constantly and tried to keep text conversations going to show how much I cared. But for some reason, the more that I tried, the less the affection was reciprocated. It took me a while to understand that I was trying too hard. And that never works. Needless to say, there is a difference between trying too hard and putting in an effort. An example of the former is neglecting too much of your life to chase a relationship and an example of the latter is understanding your value but still listening and responding thoughtfully when needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not to say that a relation or friendship can’t be ninety percent on one end and ten percent on the other. Just not all the time. Sometimes, friends have rough periods in their life and need more affection. And that's okay. Perhaps, one of the most valuable commodities a person could offer another is a continuum of unconditional care. Simply being there for them. Listening to them. Telling them that it is going to be okay, even when it might not be. Perhaps, that is something many of us overlook. I don’t know though – I’m still trying to find balance in my own life. But I think I’m learning. And that’s pretty sweet.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="2020"></category><category term="passion"></category><category term="life"></category><category term="balance"></category></entry><entry><title>BOJACK HORSEMAN</title><link href="/2020/04/bojack-horseman/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-04-04T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-04-04T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>EDIE YE</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-04-04:/2020/04/bojack-horseman/</id><summary type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Usually when people ask how I’m doing, the real answer is I’m doing shitty, but I can’t say I’m doing shitty, because I don’t even have a good reason to be doing shitty. So if I say, “I’m doing shitty” then they say, “why …&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Usually when people ask how I’m doing, the real answer is I’m doing shitty, but I can’t say I’m doing shitty, because I don’t even have a good reason to be doing shitty. So if I say, “I’m doing shitty” then they say, “why? what’s wrong?” And I have to be like, “ I don’t know, all of it?” So instead, when people ask me how I’m doing, I usually say, “I am doing so great.”- BoJack  &lt;a href="https://www.pinterest.pt/pin/720364902878836038/"&gt;img&lt;/a&gt; (Season 5, Episode 6)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are unfamiliar with &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/BoJack_Horseman"&gt;BoJack Horseman&lt;/a&gt;, it is a dark, animated comedy encompassing a horse named BoJack (I know you couldn't tell from the title). He was previously a major celebrity – a direct result of his role in the 1990s sitcom Horsin' Around – and even more previously, a victim of childhood abuse. The show is brilliant for its capture of real-life obstacles (i.e. depression, trauma, self-destructive behavior, addiction, sexuality, and racism) that many humans face as we traverse through this thing called life. I applaud the show for its role on the destigmatization of mental health and rather than write a summary of the story, largely because I believe you should go watch it yourself if you haven't already, I have decided to use the allotted space (i.e. this site) to share my favorite quotes from the six seasons. As there will be spoilers, I have divided the quotes into sections by season and if you have a favorite quote that I missed, feel free to &lt;a href="mailto:edieye_blog@hotmail.com"&gt;email&lt;/a&gt; me. I have also attached, for those available, an image or video of the dialogue between the characters to jog your memory of its relevance in the story. I take no credit for any of the images or videos used – I am solely compiling this information for myself and other fans of the show.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;TABLE OF CONTENTS &lt;a name="BACK"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="#ONE"&gt;SEASON 1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="#TWO"&gt;SEASON 2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="#THREE"&gt;SEASON 3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="#FOUR"&gt;SEASON 4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="#FIVE"&gt;SEASON 5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="#SIX"&gt;SEASON 6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;SEASON 1 &lt;a name="ONE"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diane : "You're responsible for your own happiness, you know?" &lt;br&gt;
BoJack : “God, that’s depressing.” &lt;a href="https://pin.it/5giWmZU"&gt;img&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2WELLE2nptU"&gt;vid&lt;/a&gt; (Episode 1)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BoJack : "Life is just one long hard kick in the urethra." &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kGT7DGOsOV8"&gt;vid&lt;/a&gt; (Episode 1)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BoJack : “You know what the problem is with everybody? They all just want to hear what they already believe. No one ever wants to hear the truth.” &lt;a href="https://pin.it/2bU51iE"&gt;img&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br&gt;
Diane : "I want to hear the truth. I don't know if you want to tell it though." (Episode 2)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BoJack : "Maybe because you're skinny, and maybe because you're pretty, you're used to getting away with things. But I want you to know that your actions have an effect on others, and I hate you, and you are a horrible person, and not understanding that you're a horrible person does not make you less of a horrible person." &lt;a href="https://yarn.co/yarn-clip/39c6f12f-f16e-4913-b7c7-8d786e8071c9"&gt;vid&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Pam : "You think I'm pretty?" (Episode 2)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BoJack : "People usually don't want to hang out with me after rehab. I'm really more of a before rehab friend." (Episode 3)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BoJack : "The most important thing is you got to give the people what they want. Even if it kills you, even if it empties you out until there's nothing left to empty. No matter what happens, no matter how much it hurts, you don't stop dancing, and you don't stop smiling, and you give those people what they want." (Episode 3)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sarah Lynn's Mother : "Honey, college is for ugly people who can't tap-dance." &lt;a href="https://getyarn.io/yarn-clip/011f144c-3d1e-48d4-8e5a-21d1a5fe9aa6"&gt;vid&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br&gt;
Sarah Lynn : "I want to be an architect." &lt;br&gt;
Sarah Lynn's Mother : "Sweetheart, Mommy didn't do what Mommy did to that star search producer so that you could be an architect." (Episode 3)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wayne : "You can live your happy Zelda life in this happy Zelda town and pretend you're a happy Zelda, but I know you, and this isn't you.&lt;br&gt;
Wayne : People don't change, Diane, not really. Mr. Peanutbutter's a Zelda. He's happy and he's carefree and he's loving, but you and me, we're Zoes... We're Zoes, Diane. &lt;a href="https://horseman-bojack.tumblr.com/image/159878291244"&gt;img&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Wayne : We're cynical and we're sad and we're mean. There's a darkness inside you, and you can bury it deep in burritos as big as your head, but someday soon, that darkness is gonna come out, and when it does, I want you to call me." (Episode 4)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BoJack : "What's great about Los Angeles is nobody cares where you're from or who you are. It's a superficial town where you can worry about stupid shit like keeping your pool clean, and what artisanal nuts to put on your salad." (Episode 5)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BoJack : "That's not true. I can express feelings." &lt;br&gt;
BoJack : "Nothing on the outside. Nothing on the inside." &lt;a href="https://www.pinterest.ca/pin/518265869593459040/"&gt;img&lt;/a&gt; (Episode 6)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Herb : "You know what your problem is? You want to think of yourself as the good guy. Well, I know you better than anyone, and I can tell you that you're not. In fact, you'd probably sleep a lot better at night if you just admit to yourself that you're a selfish, goddamn coward who takes whatever he want, and doesn't give a shit about who he hurts! That's you!" (Episode 8)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BoJack : "Um, I-I guess my question is do you... do you think it's too late for me?" &lt;br&gt;
Diane : "What?" &lt;br&gt;
BoJack : "I mean a-a-a-a-a-a-am I just doomed to be the person that I am? Th-The person in that book? I mean i-it's not too late for me, is it? It's not too late? Diane, I need you to tell me it's not too late." &lt;br&gt;
Diane : "BoJack, I..." &lt;br&gt;
BoJack : "I-I-I-I need you to tell me that I'm a good person. I know that I can be selfish and narcissistic and self-destructive, but underneath all that, deep down, I'm a good person, and I need you to tell me that I'm good. Diane? Tell me, please, Diane. Tell me that I'm good." &lt;a href="https://www.pinterest.ca/pin/554787247825806112/"&gt;img&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=45a1NTArG-g"&gt;vid&lt;/a&gt; (Episode 11)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diane : "BoJack, when people find out that someone like you, who seems larger than life, is actually just as wounded and vulnerable as they are, it makes them feel less lonely." (Episode 11)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BoJack : "This is my last chance to make people love me again. If this goes out, everybody's gonna see the real me. Now, I spend a lot of time with the real me, and believe me, nobody's gonna love that guy." (Episode 11)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Todd : "As you know, I was hurt. But then I realised, that's just how you are. You know, and maybe I just need to stop expecting you to be a good person, so that way I won't get hurt when you're not." (Episode 11)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diane : "It's never too late to be the person you want to be. You need to choose the life you want." &lt;a href="https://pin.it/5nvxmxw"&gt;img&lt;/a&gt; (Episode 11)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diane : "Well, That's the problem with life, right? Either you know what you want, and then you don't get what you want. Or you get what you want, and then you don't know what you want." (Episode 12)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diane : "That's the thing - I don't think I believe in deep down. I kind of think all you are is just the things that you do." &lt;a href="https://weheartit.com/entry/320307627"&gt;img&lt;/a&gt; (Episode 12)
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="#BACK"&gt;BACK TO TABLE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;SEASON 2 &lt;a name="TWO"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beatrice Horseman : "You better grow up to be something great, to make up for all the damage you've done." (Episode 1)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beatrice Horseman : "I just wanted to tell you... I know. I know you wanna be happy, but you won't be, and... I'm sorry. It's not just you, you know. Your father and I, we, well... You come by it, honestly, the ugliness inside you. I know you you were born broken, that's your birthright. And now you can fill your life with projects. Your books and your movies and your little girlfriends but it won't make you whole. You're BoJack. There's no cure for that." &lt;a href="https://pin.it/3Lfyrxw"&gt;img&lt;/a&gt; (Episode 1)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Princess Carolyn : "You know a lot of people go their whole lives and they never give a damn. But Herb, he gave those beavers a dam." (Episode 3)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BoJack : "Yea, I'm calling this road-trip a double-O seven, because we are going to bond." (Episode 5)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mr.Peanutbutter : "Team players wanted"? Oh, I'm such a good team player, I make all the other team players look like garbage." (Episode 6)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mr. Peanutbutter : "All I ever wanted was to be your friend. And you treat me like a big joke. You think I don't notice? Why don't you like me?" &lt;br&gt;
BoJack : "Mr. Peanutbutter..."
Mr. Peanutbutter : "No, tell me." &lt;br&gt;
BoJack : "Because... "I'm jealous." &lt;br&gt;
Mr. Peanutbutter : "Oh. Of what? Diane?" &lt;br&gt;
BoJack : "No. Of everything. Everything comes so easy for you." &lt;br&gt;
Mr. Peanutbutter : "Oh, and it doesn't for you? You're a millionaire movie star with a girlfriend who loves you, acting in your dream movie. What more do you want? What else could the universe possible owe you?" &lt;br&gt;
BoJack : "I want... to feel good about myself. The way you do. And I don't know how. I don't know if I can." &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zIeGfsTbofM"&gt;vid&lt;/a&gt; (Episode 8)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wanda Pierce : "What happened, BoJack?" &lt;br&gt;
BoJack : "Same thing that always happens. You didn't know me and then you fell in love with me. And now you know me." &lt;br&gt;
Wanda Pierce : "When you look at the world through rose-colored glasses, all the red flags just look like flags." &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=huPtWcb982o"&gt;vid&lt;/a&gt; (Episode 10)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Charlotte : “I don't care where you go, BoJack, but I can't have you around here, you make me too sad." (Episode 11)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BoJack : "I don't understand how people... live. It's amazing to me that people wake up every morning and say: 'Yeah, another day, let's do it.' How do people do it? I don't know how." &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4m3MrfnCecg"&gt;vid&lt;/a&gt; (Episode 11)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rutabaga Rabitowitz : "Can you really afford to be picky? What? I'm just saying, what, you think you're gonna find some perfect unattached guy who's gonna love you like I do? Who's gonna make you laugh and feel good about yourself? This is it, Carolyn, this is what you get. If you're holding out for something better, well, I hate to break it to you, but you're gonna be alone for a long time." (Episode 11)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BoJack : "Ow, crap. I hate this. Running is terrible, everything is the worst." &lt;br&gt;
BoJack : "Oh my God, oh my God." &lt;br&gt;
Jogging baboon : “It gets easier. Every day it gets a little easier. But you gotta do it every day —that’s the hard part. But it does get easier." &lt;a href="https ://www.youtube.com/watch?v=R2_Mn-qRKjA"&gt;vid&lt;/a&gt; (Episode 12)
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="#BACK"&gt;BACK TO TABLE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;SEASON 3 &lt;a name="THREE"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BoJack : "How do you make something right when you’ve made it so wrong you can never go back." &lt;br&gt;
Reporter : "I think you have to keep moving forward?" &lt;br&gt;
BoJack : "All my life that’s all I’ve ever done. What’s it gotten me?" (Episode 1)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diane : "It’s not about being happy, that is the thing. I’m just trying to get through each day. I can’t keep asking myself 'Am I happy?' It just makes me more miserable. I don’t know If I believe in it, real lasting happiness, All those perky, well-adjusted people you see in movies and TV shows ? I don’t think they exist." (Episode 3)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BoJack : "No one’s happy all the time, you have to focus on the small things." (Episode 3)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diane : "Everyone was worried about you, you know. You can’t just disappear. You really hurt a lot of people." &lt;br&gt;
Cuddlywhiskers : "Sometimes you need to take responsibility for you own happiness." &lt;br&gt;
Diane : "You don't think that's a little selfish?" &lt;br&gt;
Cuddlywhiskers : "I don’t know what to tell you. I’m happy for the first time in my life and I’m not gonna feel bad about it. It takes a long time to realize how truly miserable you are and even longer to see it doesn’t have to be that way. Only after you give up everything can you begin to find a way to be happy." &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0FOtyg7lnrE"&gt;vid&lt;/a&gt; (Episode 3)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BoJack : "Kelsey, in this terrifying world, all we have are the connections we make. I'm sorry I got you fired. I'm sorry I never called you after." (Episode 4)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BoJack : "Taneisha, nobody completes anybody. That's not a real thing! If you're lucky enough to find someone you can halfway tolerate, you sink your nails in and you don't let go, no matter what." &lt;br&gt;
Taneisha : "So what? I should just... settle?" &lt;br&gt;
BoJack : "Yes! Thank you, exactly: settle! Because, otherwise, you're just gonna get older and harder and more alone. And you're gonna do everything you can to fill that hole- with friends and your career and meaningless sex, but the hole... doesn't get filled. And one day you're going to look around and you're going to realize that everybody loves you... but nobody likes you. And that is the loneliest feeling in the world." &lt;a href="https://www.pinterest.ca/pin/686517536929968421/"&gt;img&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1zszD_-xM2w"&gt;vid&lt;/a&gt; (Episode 5)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diane : "... and sometimes I think I know myself, but maybe that's a trap. Because maybe I am Cool Sexy Diane or Really in Touch with Her Feelings Diane or possibly other Dianes we don't even know about yet. The point is, I am all of the Dianes." (Episode 5)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The closer : "When you do bad things, you have something you can point to when people eventually leave you. It’s not you, you tell yourself. It’s that bad thing you did. Do you often keep people at arm’s length? Are you afraid of being known and knowing others?" (Episode 7)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BoJack : "Yeah, she was right. It’s so sad when you see someone as they really are, it ruins them." &lt;a href="https://weheartit.com/entry/326961336"&gt;img&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://tv.getyarn.io/yarn-clip/8a262b07-7f39-4327-98c0-c926be043a58"&gt;vid&lt;/a&gt; (Episode 7)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The closer : "No, because that’s just theater. It allows you to think you’re in control but the whole idea of control is a myth. The universe is a wild beast. You can’t tame it. All you can do is try to live inside it." (Episode 7)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mr Peanutbutter : "It's so cruel to let people love you. All you're doing is promising you'll one day break their hearts." &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=40figWEmK38"&gt;vid&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.pinterest.ca/pin/355995545539724391/"&gt;img&lt;/a&gt; (Episode 8)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BoJack : "You like being there to rescue me. Because it makes you feel good about yourself Princess Carolyn. Please, you’re such a self-pitying masochist, I could say ten nice things and one mean thing and you would only hear the one mean thing." (Episode 9)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BoJack : "You know that I don’t do the whole love thing. Either you end up hurting someone or they hurt you. So what’s the point?" (Episode 9)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Princess Carolyn : "Your heart is tender, so you protect it from people, but sometimes you open up a wall and it’s incredible. You’re doing the best you can considering your asshole parents." (Episode 9)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BoJack : "Just 'cause you're good at something doesn't mean you have to do it. I'm good at driving sober, but I don't relish the opportunity."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ana : "BoJack, don’t do this. Don’t fetishize your own sadness." (Episode 10)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BoJack : "Todd, I'm sorry, alright? I screwed up, I- I know I screwed up, I—" &lt;br&gt;
Todd : "Oh great, of course! Here it comes! You can't keep doing this! You can't keep doing shitty things and then feel bad about yourself like that makes it okay! You need to be better!" &lt;br&gt;
BoJack : "I know, and I'm sorry, okay? I was drunk and there was all this pressure with the Oscar campaign, but now that it's over, I- I- I—" &lt;br&gt;
Todd : "No! No, BoJack, just stop. You are all the things that are wrong with you. It’s not the alcohol or the drugs or any of the shitty things that happened to you in your career or when you were a kid. It’s you. Alright, it’s you. Fuck man, what else is there to say." &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ohoLzH9EQzg"&gt;vid&lt;/a&gt; (Episode 10)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Random bird : "And I realized people don’t change because they want to change. They change because they have to change." (Episode 11)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sara-Lynn : "Hey, we have all done shitty stuff before. Most of us aren’t as proud of it as you seem to be." (Episode 11)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sarah Lynn : [her final words] "I want to be an architect." (Episode 11)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BoJack : "See, Sarah Lynn? We're not doomed. In the grand scheme of things, we're just tiny specks that will one day be forgotten. So it doesn't matter what we did in the past, or how we'll be remembered. The only thing that matters is right now. This moment. This one spectacular moment we are sharing together. Right, Sarah Lynn? Sarah Lynn? Sarah Lynn?" &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=o6ml5FdnXiA"&gt;vid&lt;/a&gt; (Episode 11)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ana : "There are going to be times when you’ll see someone in trouble. You’re going to want to rush in there and do whatever you can to save them, but you have to stop yourself. Because there are some people you can’t save. Cause those people will thrash and struggle and try to take you down with them." (Episode 11)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BoJack : "Liquor before beer." &lt;br&gt;
BoJack : "Never fear." &lt;br&gt;
BoJack : "Don't do heroin." (Episode 11)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BoJack : "I don’t know how to be Diane. It doesn’t get better and it doesn’t get easier. I can’t keep lying to myself thinking I’m gonna change, I’m poison. I come from poison and I have poison inside me and I destroy everything I touch. That’s my legacy. I have nothing to show for the live I have lived. And I have nobody in my life who’s better off for having known me." &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fVFROLk7ZBU"&gt;vid&lt;/a&gt; (Episode 12)
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="#BACK"&gt;BACK TO TABLE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;SEASON 4 &lt;a name="FOUR"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eddie : "Where are you going?" &lt;br&gt;
BoJack : "Home." (Episode 2)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hollyhock : "Ever since I was a baby, people have always said that I kind of look like BoJack." &lt;br&gt;
Todd : "Oh my god! That is a terrible thing to say to a baby!" (Episode 3)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BoJack : "But now I can feel her getting attached, and I just know I'm gonna BoJack things up." &lt;br&gt;
Mr. Peanutbutter : "BoJack things up? You mean, show up somewhere and be the life of the party? Then share a laugh with your good friend, Mr. Peanutbutter?" &lt;br&gt;
BoJack : "No, obviously I meant screw everything up until she hates me. I don't think I can take that. Maybe this time, don't do the thing that makes her hate you. I don't want to, but every time she looks at me with those big innocent eyes, all I can think about is every shitty thing I've ever done, and I think, 'I don't deserve that kind of love'." (Episode 6)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BoJack : "You're a piece of shit, but at least I know I'm a piece of shit, that makes me better than those other pieces of shit who don't know they're pieces of shit." (Episode 6)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BoJack : "Hollyhock, I'm glad you're here. If I'm shitty, that's just because I'm shitty, and you're allowed to be mad at me. But you need to know that whatever I do, it's not your fault." &lt;br&gt;
Hollyhock : "I know. I mean, I know, but I don't always know, you know? Like sometimes I have this tiny voice in the back of my head that goes like, 'Hey, everyone hates you, and they're not wrong to feel that way.'" &lt;br&gt;
BoJack : "I know what you mean." &lt;br&gt;
Hollyhock : "That voice... the one that tells you you're worthless and stupid and ugly?" &lt;br&gt;
BoJack : "Yeah?" &lt;br&gt;
Hollyhock  : "It goes away, right? It's just like, a dumb teenage girl thing, but then it goes away?" &lt;br&gt;
BoJack : "Yeah." &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1ZGmmvgIMNk"&gt;vid&lt;/a&gt; (Episode 6)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BoJack : "You can be mad at me or you can get drunk with me, but you can't do both." &lt;br&gt;
Diane : "Watch me." (Episode 7)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jessica Biel : "The rule of man is over, now begins the rule of fire! I will no longer be shackled by the civilized society of the above ground. This is Underground and the only law here is flame. The fire wants not for justice, the fire wants not for reason, the fire desires only to be fed! Feed the fire!" (Episode 7)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Princess Carolyn : "Sometimes life is like the second season of Friday Night Lights. You have to push through and hope there's better stuff ahead." (Episode 7)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BoJack : "Okay, okay. Here's the secret to being happy." &lt;br&gt;
Diane : "Oh, I can't wait to hear this." &lt;br&gt;
BoJack : "Just pretend you are happy, and eventually you'll forget you're pretending." (Episode 7)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Princess Carolyn : "Hey, you know what I do when I have really, bad, awful, terrible day?" &lt;br&gt;
BoJack : "What?" &lt;br&gt;
Princess Carolyn : "I imagine my great, great, great granddaughter in the future talking to her class about me, she's poised and funny and tells people about me and how everything's worked out in the end, and when I think about that I think about how everything's going to work out because how else could she tell people?" &lt;br&gt;
BoJack : "But it's... fake." &lt;br&gt;
Princess Carolyn : "Yeah well... it makes me feel better." (Episode 9)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Todd : "Call me 4 out of 5 dentists, 'cause I agree!" (Episode 12)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Todd : "The woods are dark and scary, but the only way out is through!" &lt;a href="https://i.imgur.com/vk3C0z1.jpg"&gt;img&lt;/a&gt; (Episode 12)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diane : "You know, sometimes I feel like our marriage is like a Magic Eye poster." &lt;br&gt;
Mr. Peanutbutter : "I love those things." &lt;br&gt;
Diane : "I know. And it's messy. and at first glance, it doesn't seem to make any sense. And it's hard to figure out. But sometimes, if you squint at it just right, everything lines up, and it's the most perfect... beautiful, amazing thing." &lt;br&gt;
Mr. Peanutbutter : "Yeah. I know what you mean." &lt;br&gt;
Diane : "But..." &lt;br&gt;
Diane : "I'm so tired of squinting." &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iMFIehwHpSo"&gt;vid&lt;/a&gt; (Episode 12)
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="#BACK"&gt;BACK TO TABLE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;SEASON 5 &lt;a name="FIVE"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diane: "The real reason you go to Vietnam is because you see your accidentally soon-to-be ex-husband kiss someone else. At first you think, 'Oh, it's a fling. Whatever, they're drunk, it's a party. But then he puts his hand on the small of her back exactly the way he used to do to you. It means
I've got you, and when he did it to you, it made you feel safe.' And you realize he will never do that to you again.  And it breaks your heart, again after you heart was so broken that you thought it could never get anymore broken. You thought it was safe but it still, somehow, finds a new way to break. Because, even though you're the one who asked for this, now that you've got it, you are completely adrift with no compass, or map, or sense of where to go, or what to do. So you go to Vietnam. You think you might find community, a connection to something bigger, but.. you don't. In fact, you feel even more alone than you were before you left. But... you survive. You learn that you can survive being alone. &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1i2vgV7VSuk"&gt;vid&lt;/a&gt; (Episode 2)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BoJack : "Once again, my life has been worsened by a brush with musical theater." (Episode 3)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BoJack : "Beatrice Horseman was born in 1938, and she died in 2018, and I have no idea... what she wanted. Unless she just wanted what we all want: to be seen." (Episode 6)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BoJack : "We understood each other in a way, me and my mom and my dad. As screwed up as we all were, we did understand each other. My mother, she knew what it's like to feel your entire life like you're drowning with the exception of these moments, these very rare, brief instances, in which you suddenly remember... you can swim." &lt;br&gt;
BoJack : "But then again, mostly not. Mostly you're drowning. She understood that, too. And she recognized that I understood it. And Dad. All three of us were drowning, and we didn't know how to save each other, but there was an understanding that we were all drowning together." (Episode 6)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Butterscotch Horseman : "No, it's not her fault. She's doing the best she can, after all. It's just that, you can't depend on women. You can't depend on anyone. Sooner or later, you need to learn that no one else is gonna take care of you. That's what I learned when I had to make my own sandwich. You can't rely on other people, BoJack. It's good for you to know. And she's a good mother for teaching you that. You've got a head start on most kids. You're actually very lucky." (Episode 6)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BoJack : "I was in the hospital with her those last moments, and they were truly horrifying, full of nonsensical screams and cries, but there was this moment, this one instant of strange calm, where she looked in my direction and said, "I see you." That's the last thing she said to me. "I see you." Not a statement of judgment or disappointment, just acceptance and the simple recognition of another person in a room. "Hello, there. You are a person. And I see you." Let me tell you, it's a weird thing to feel at 54 years old, that for the first time in your life, your mother sees you. It's an odd realization that that's the thing you've been missing, the only thing you wanted all along, to be seen. And it doesn't feel like a relief, to finally be seen. It feels mean, like, "Oh, it turns out that you knew what I wanted, and you waited until the very last moment to give it to me." I was prepared for more cruelty. I was sure that she would get in one final zinger about how I let her down, and about how I was fat and stupid, and too tall to be an effective Lindy-hopper. How I was needy and a burden and an embarrassment. All that I was ready for. I was not ready for "I see you." Only my mother would be lousy enough to swipe me with a moment of connection on her way out. But maybe I'm giving her too much credit. Maybe it wasn't about connection. Maybe it was a... maybe it was an "I see you," like, "I see you." Like, "You might have the rest of the world fooled, but I know exactly who you are." That's more my mom's speed. Or maybe she just literally meant "I see you. You are an object that has entered my field of vision." She was pretty out of it at the end, so maybe it's dumb to try to attribute it to anything." (Episode 6)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Todd : "I guess we'd hang out together, like we already do, and you'd be my favorite person, like you already are. And when something good happened to me, like if I got a promotion at work, you'd be the first person I'd tell. And you'd smile and say, 'That's my boyfriend.'" (Episode 9)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gina Cazador : "You don't want that. For everything to be fine? How dreadfully boring." (Episode 11)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BoJack : "I don't understand why you're being so nice to me. After everything you know about me, and all the shit I've put you through. &lt;br&gt;
Diane : When I was in high school, I had this friend. Abby. She was my only friend and we did everything together. Until she got adopted by the cool kids, and then she turned on me, so fast. She used every secret she knew about me, every vulnerability. She made me miserable my entire sophomore year. But then that summer, when her mom got sick, like really sick, and all her cool friends were off vacationing in Martha's Vineyard, I was there for her." &lt;br&gt;
BoJack : "Why?" &lt;br&gt;
Diane : "Because I'm an idiot. And it was Abby. And I hated her, and I will never forgive her, but she needed me, and... she was my best friend, and I loved her. And now... you're here, and I hate you, but you're my best friend, and you need me." (Episode 12)
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="#BACK"&gt;BACK TO TABLE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;SEASON 6 &lt;a name="SIX"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Princess Carolyn : "We have so much in common. I don't know why we've spent so many years hating each other." &lt;br&gt;
Vanessa Gekko : "I never hated you. Do you hate me?" &lt;br&gt;
Princess Carolyn : [lying] "Uh, no." (Episode 2)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diane : "When I was a little girl, I thought that everything - all the abuse and neglect - it somehow made me special. And I decided that one day, I would write something that made little girls like me less alone... And if I can't write that book..." (Episode 10)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diane : “That means that all the damage I got isn’t ‘good damage.’ It’s just damage.” &lt;br&gt;
Diane : “I could have been happy this whole time and written books about girl detectives and been cheerful and popular had good parents… What was it all for?!” (Episode 10)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BoJack : "This place was supposed to be a fresh start for me. Rehab was supposed to be a fresh start. But no matter how many starts I get, there's always the same ending. Everything falls apart, and I end up alone." &lt;br&gt;
Princess Carolyn : "I'm still here, BoJack." &lt;br&gt;
BoJack : "Why?" &lt;br&gt;
Princess Carolyn : "I don't know. I'm a fool, I guess. And you were my first client. And one time you were drunk and you smiled at me, and I said: 'What?'' And you said: 'I just like being in a room with you. You make rooms good.'" &lt;br&gt;
BoJack : "You still do." &lt;br&gt;
Princess Carolyn : "I have loved you for 25 years, and I never loved anyone better. That kind of love, you only get it when you're young and stupid. I'm not gonna get it again. And when I tell my daughter the story of the great love of my life, I want it to have a happy ending." &lt;br&gt;
BoJack : "Is it possible you letting me go is the happy ending?" (Episode 11)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BoJack : "I’ve had a lot of what I thought were rock bottoms, only to discover another rockier bottom underneath.... Eventually, I decided to stop waiting for something to change me. I had to make the change myself." (Episode 12)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BoJack : "Less talkie and more coffee." (Episode 13)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BoJack : "See you on the other side." &lt;br&gt;
Herb Kazzaz : "Oh, BoJack... no. There is no other side. This is it." (Episode 15)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diane : "It's too late. What's done is done." &lt;br&gt;
BoJack : "No." &lt;br&gt;
Diane : "There's nothing I can do, BoJack. I'm not real. None of this is." &lt;br&gt;
BoJack : "So, what do I do now?" &lt;br&gt;
Diane : "BoJack, it doesn't matter." &lt;br&gt;
BoJack : "Well, if it doesn't matter, can I stay on the phone with you at least?" &lt;br&gt;
Diane : "Okay. &lt;br&gt;
BoJack : "How was your day? &lt;br&gt;
Diane : "Good." &lt;br&gt;
BoJack : "Yeah?" &lt;br&gt;
Diane : "Yeah. My day was good." (Episode 15)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Todd: "But isn't the point of art less what people put into it and more what people get out of it?" &lt;br&gt;
BoJack: "Is that the point of art?" &lt;br&gt;
Todd: "Maybe, or maybe art doesn't need a point. Maybe that's why it's called art." &lt;br&gt;
BoJack : "I can't tell if you're being smart or stupid." &lt;br&gt;
Todd : "Oh, I never know." &lt;br&gt;
BoJack : "I think you had it for a moment, and then you lost it." &lt;br&gt;
Todd : "Oh, well. It was nice while it lasted, right?" &lt;br&gt;
BoJack : "Sure. It was nice while it lasted." &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hN24urQktVE"&gt;vid&lt;/a&gt; (Episode 16)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diane : "No, I need to tell you... thank you... and... it's going to be okay... and... I'm sorry... and... thank you..." (Episode 16)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diane : "I wish I could have been the person you thought I was, the person who would save you." &lt;br&gt;
BoJack : "That was never your job." &lt;br&gt;
Diane : "Then why did you always make me feel like it was? I don't know, maybe it's everyone's job to save each other. I don't know. Anyway, I am glad you're alive." (Episode 16)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BoJack : "How'd you learn how to trust it? The happiness?"&lt;br&gt;
Diane : "I didn't. But I trust him." (Episode 16)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diane : "I think there are people that help you become the person that you end up being, and you can be grateful for them, even if they were never meant to be in your life forever." &lt;br&gt;
Diane : I'm glad i knew you too." &lt;br&gt;
BoJack : "Knew, huh?" &lt;br&gt;
Diane : "Mm" &lt;br&gt;
BoJack : "Hey, wouldn't it be funny if this night was the last time we ever talked to each other?" (Episode 16)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BoJack : "Life's a bitch and then you die, right?" &lt;br&gt;
 Diane : "Sometimes. Sometimes life's a bitch and then you keep living." &lt;br&gt;
BoJack : "Yeah." &lt;br&gt;
Diane : "But it's a nice night, huh?" &lt;br&gt;
BoJack : "Yeah. This is nice." &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KNpY-RrY2A4"&gt;vid&lt;/a&gt; (Episode 16)
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="#BACK"&gt;BACK TO TABLE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><category term="2020"></category><category term="BoJack"></category><category term="Horseman"></category><category term="life"></category><category term="quotes"></category></entry><entry><title>MY MOM</title><link href="/2020/03/my-mom/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-03-09T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-03-09T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>EDIE YE</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-03-09:/2020/03/my-mom/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;My mom is very powerful for a woman in her fifties. Let me rephrase that — my mom is very powerful, period. This is not because she practices &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tai_chi"&gt;Tai chi&lt;/a&gt; (despite this being how she sees it), but because of her ability to shut me up by just looking at me …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;My mom is very powerful for a woman in her fifties. Let me rephrase that — my mom is very powerful, period. This is not because she practices &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tai_chi"&gt;Tai chi&lt;/a&gt; (despite this being how she sees it), but because of her ability to shut me up by just looking at me. I don't know if the calm, infamous stare is a parenting technique or an asian parenting technique; the only certainty is that the calm stare is fueled by anger that can and will end me, if needed. The beauty, however, is in the inverse relationship between how angry she is and how calm she appears — the calmer she is, the more angry she eventually will become. It is ever so frightening simply because I love my mom an abnormal amount – more than I am willing to tell her. It probably has to do with her almost giving me up for adoption when I was younger. Just kidding. She could never. She is an incredible woman and mom despite me not being the best child growing up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the former years of elementary school, it was pretty much social suicide to display any form of affection to a person of the opposite gender, let alone your mom. This was very apparent when my mom continued to pick me up and greet me with a hug after school – even in the third grade. I mean, it was fine between kindergarten and the second grade, but by the third (come on now), I was basically as grown and as independent as I am today. Despite that day being more than a decade ago, I still remember it clearly. I remember how she beamed with joy and how her arms were wide open as she approached me, as if she was a human shield sheltering me from the cruel world that surrounded us. But nope. &lt;em&gt;Absolutely not.&lt;/em&gt; Her little boy had grown up. I ducked to elude the warm hug she tried to greet me with, smiled and said “not here, mom.” Little did I know that my actions were colder than day old oatmeal and I could still see the hurt in her face to this day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am lucky because she either doesn’t remember or she chooses not to remind me of that experience. Come to think of it, my mom is much cooler than I am. Aside from her great affection for her children and her incredible will to practice Tai Chi, she volunteers a bunch and has a good number of friends. Her jam-packed schedule and her ability to follow through with it every day is a demonstration of her tenacity and a reminder that I have yet to live up to my potential. I honestly would be lying if I said I wasn’t a bit jealous of how courageous she was, having transitioned to a foreign country with not a dollar to her name in an attempt to build a better life for her and her family. This is not to say she does not nag me constantly or pull rank on me to remind me where I stand because she does – and she does a damn good job of it. However, my relationship with my mom and our understanding of each other has gotten better over the years, but like all things, it has and will continue to have its share of struggle and hardship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;It was tough growing up.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lunch was awful. Just awful. For a good part of my elementary years, she packed leftover rice, huge portions of vegetables, and smeared bits of meat – it was garbage made with love and she had the audacity to call it &lt;em&gt;lunch.&lt;/em&gt; The vegetable to meat ratio was so embarrassing that I refuse to share that information to this day. On top of that, a good portion of my classmates had sandwiches for lunch – so you can imagine the discomfort I felt standing out, eating my &lt;em&gt;love-filled rice.&lt;/em&gt; I remember how elated I felt when I was able to convince her to start packing sandwiches for lunch. On that day, I opened my lunch box to reveal black forest ham and a single cheese slice stuck between two soggy whole-wheat pieces of bread; the bread might as well have been one-hundred percent whole-wheat because I was one-hundred percent not satisfied. I could feel my blood boil – the eight-year old me just wanted a decent lunch. I mentally prepared myself to yell at her that very night as I gobbled away at the sandwich. That said, the moment she got home from work, I sensed how tired she was and how insatiable I was being that I decided not to bring it up. When she asked me how the sandwich tasted, I told her it was great. This is the story of how I ended up eating soggy sandwiches for lunch, but it makes me happy reflecting on this story simply because the sandwiches were made with maternal love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;School was easy but those years were tough. My clothes were hand-me-downs from my older siblings and or cousins. My mom rarely ever bought new toys and gaming consoles were out of the question. It took me a long time to swallow the hard truth that my mom didn’t buy me nice things not because she didn’t love me, but simply because we couldn’t afford them. It was tough for her – she worked two jobs for a good part of my childhood to make ends meet. Everytime I think about how much she sacrificed and how much she will continue to sacrifice, I am reminded of how fortunate I am – so yes, between you and me, I love my mom. I have yet to say those three words to her though. I don’t know – it’s complicated.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="2020"></category><category term="love"></category><category term="mom"></category><category term="life"></category></entry><entry><title>THE BIGGEST LIE</title><link href="/2020/02/the-biggest-lie/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-02-17T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2020-02-17T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>EDIE YE</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-02-17:/2020/02/the-biggest-lie/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest lies I tell myself is I’ll start enjoying myself—I’ll start living—once I finish
this task or when that event happens. This and that. Wait. It’s almost as if my mind doesn’t want
me to live my life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What do I …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest lies I tell myself is I’ll start enjoying myself—I’ll start living—once I finish
this task or when that event happens. This and that. Wait. It’s almost as if my mind doesn’t want
me to live my life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What do I mean? I mean I keep trying to set myself up. I justify my struggle with an end goal. I tell myself once I finish highschool, once I graduate from university, once I find my significant other, once I start my mortgage–I’ll start living. It’s a means to an end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t want to wake up one day not having really lived my life. I don’t want to wake up one day wondering why time passed so &lt;em&gt;damn fast.&lt;/em&gt; I don’t want to be nostalgic of a life that I never even lived.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I always tell myself I know the perfect life exists–I just need to finish everything at hand. Then I’ll be happy. I tell myself the vision of an ideal life is within my grasp—I just need to skip some pages of my story. I have become so enamoured with looking ahead that I have forgotten to live for the now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to start treasuring things. I want to start treasuring every late night conversation I have, every sunset and sunrise I witness, and every opportunity I get to spend with my family and friends. Because this is it. This is my life. I better start enjoying the small moments that make me feel alive because one day I’ll be in the ground and it’ll all be over, you know?&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="2020"></category><category term="mental health"></category><category term="self"></category><category term="life"></category><category term="self love"></category></entry><entry><title>NINE THINGS TO DO TO FEEL BETTER ABOUT YOURSELF</title><link href="/2020/01/nine-things-to-do-to-feel-better-about-yourself/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-01-19T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2020-01-19T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>EDIE YE</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-01-19:/2020/01/nine-things-to-do-to-feel-better-about-yourself/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Lately, I have been researching about mental health and the problems that can arise from individuals with cognitive imbalances in the brain. This, in turn, made me think of what I personally do after being placed in a stressful situation. If you want to read more on why life is …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Lately, I have been researching about mental health and the problems that can arise from individuals with cognitive imbalances in the brain. This, in turn, made me think of what I personally do after being placed in a stressful situation. If you want to read more on why life is worth living, you can read more &lt;a href="https://edieye.ca/2020/01/why-you-should-go-on/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;FOCUS ON THE MOMENT&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stop—stop for a moment and try to focus entirely on a random object. For example, in front of my desk is an orange. Some questions that quickly arise are—&lt;em&gt;where did this orange come from?&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;how many hands have touched it?&lt;/em&gt;, or &lt;em&gt;was the orange fruit named after the colour?&lt;/em&gt; The answers to the questions themselves can remain a mystery but at that moment in time, I am directing my focus entirely on the orange and nothing else. As ridiculous as what you read might sound, it works simply because the orange acts as a bridge between life being complicated and life being as simple as that, an orange. Try it on something, &lt;em&gt;on anything.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;CLEAN&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clean. Clean the dishes. Clean your room and the entire house if you have to. I know, cleaning is boring and requires physical work—but think about how you will feel after you are finished. Think about how accomplished you will feel from such a simple activity. Who knows, maybe you’ll find money or an old belonging that brings back some good, old memories. If that isn’t enough, think about how a clean house will feel—an organized room, folded clothes, dust-free laptop and tables—&lt;em&gt;it’s uplifting.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;EXERCISE&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Run. Go outside of your safe space and just run as fast as you can. This will get your endorphins going which will result in happiness. Run until you are out of breath. Walk it off and repeat until you can’t run anymore. You feel yourself gasping for air? &lt;em&gt;That is what it means to be alive.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;TAKE A SHOWER&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shower. Not only is the shower a perfect place to sing your favourite songs out of tune but a place to reflect and feel sorry for yourself as well. Have a long, hot shower and cry your heart out if needed. Sit on the ground and let the hot water clean every inch of your body. Let the steam soak into your skin and just focus on breathing. That said, promise yourself that the moment you turn off the water, you will move on from whatever troubles you felt. Leave the shower with a clean slate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;WRITE&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Write on paper—with a pen—I don’t necessarily mean words. Let whatever is on your mind, whatever emotion or problem translate to the paper in front of you. Scribble furiously or draw a picture of &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Toby_Flenderson"&gt;Toby&lt;/a&gt; if you have to. Write anything and have it not make sense to anyone but &lt;strong&gt;yourself&lt;/strong&gt;. When you are done, rip the paper into tens, hundreds of pieces and watch as they fall to the floor—the paper is your enemy. Sometimes having destructive thoughts can make you feel good. Don’t carry it out for too long though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;DRINK TEA&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Boil some water and make some tea. There are so many health benefits that come with tea—I will leave this to the experts. Watch as the tea leaves disperse and change the colour of the water. Realize that watching colours change is a simple experience that we often overlook. Sit on a chair with the teacup in your hands and wait patiently for the tea to cool. Feel the warmth in your stomach as you slowly sip the tea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;BECOME THE PERSON YOU WOULD FALL IN LOVE WITH&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go outside and open doors for strangers. Smile as they walk past you. Go for a drive and let cars merge into your lane. Pay for an extra parking ticket and leave the second one in the machine. Compliment people on their clothes. Compliment them on their personality. Ask people about their day or story even. Talk to acquaintances and try not to interrupt. Become friends with them, even if there are language barriers, age gaps, or cultural differences. When you see someone struggling, act selflessly to help them. Maybe it will take the weight off of your shoulders—who knows?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;WRITE DOWN A LIST OF GOALS&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Write down a list of goals to achieve for the day or week. Start with easy tasks such as waking up, brushing your teeth, drinking water, or going for a walk. Tick them off as you finish them. Being organized in such a manner teaches you that every small task can be seen as an accomplishment, as a &lt;a href="https://edieye.ca/2020/01/what-does-success-look-like/"&gt;success&lt;/a&gt;. Not only will you feel as you are doing more than usual, which will pep your mood (woohoo), but it will teach you to take on a more structured approach to planning things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;TAKE A BREAK FROM THE INTERNET&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take a break. You can do it. Do you know how many meaningless little things you trouble yourself with? These platforms—Email, Twitter, Snapchat, Instagram, Quora, Tumblr, LinkedIn, Facebook—you can take a break from them for a few minutes. For a day even. Don’t get me wrong, these socials have changed our lives for the better but when you become so enamoured with them that you can’t take a small break for yourself, it can become tiring. &lt;em&gt;Very tiring.&lt;/em&gt; Make some time for yourself—just yourself.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="2020"></category><category term="pelican"></category><category term="mental health"></category><category term="self healing"></category><category term="self love"></category><category term="better"></category></entry><entry><title>WHAT IS THE MEANING OF LIFE</title><link href="/2020/01/what-is-the-meaning-of-life/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-01-17T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2020-01-17T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>EDIE YE</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-01-17:/2020/01/what-is-the-meaning-of-life/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have compiled a list of the two types of questions that are humanly impossible to answer, with one being &lt;a href="https://www.cut-the-knot.org/WhatIs/WhatIsAnalyticGeometry.shtml"&gt;analytic geometry&lt;/a&gt; in the third dimension (haha math is tough) and the other being questions of this form. That said, since you are already here, let me answer the impossible …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have compiled a list of the two types of questions that are humanly impossible to answer, with one being &lt;a href="https://www.cut-the-knot.org/WhatIs/WhatIsAnalyticGeometry.shtml"&gt;analytic geometry&lt;/a&gt; in the third dimension (haha math is tough) and the other being questions of this form. That said, since you are already here, let me answer the impossible to the best of my ability. Let me first ask you a few sub-questions—&lt;strong&gt;what&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;where&lt;/strong&gt; are we in the &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cosmos"&gt;cosmos&lt;/a&gt;?, &lt;strong&gt;why&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;how&lt;/strong&gt; does gravity prevent us from spinning off into space?, &lt;strong&gt;who&lt;/strong&gt; created the first form of life?, &lt;strong&gt;if&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;when&lt;/strong&gt; will time one day pass in reverse?, and &lt;strong&gt;what&lt;/strong&gt; are the ultimate limits to humans can know?
These questions, similar to the meaning of life, are difficult to answer yet have beauty because they are of the unknown. That said, maybe the meaning of life is simply, here and now. Maybe the journey—the struggling, the frustration, the hard work, and the tears themselves is the point. Maybe don't be so focused on searching for the meaning of life when the meaning of life is to give it meaning. Maybe, just maybe, the point is to avoid controlling things and just, well, &lt;em&gt;live&lt;/em&gt;. As &lt;a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt1065073/characters/nm3878243"&gt;Nicole&lt;/a&gt; would say, “You know how everyone’s always saying seize the moment? I don’t know, I’m kinda thinking its the other way around. You know, like the moment seizes us.”&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="2020"></category><category term="pelican"></category><category term="life"></category><category term="meaning"></category><category term="cosmos"></category><category term="gravity"></category><category term="moment"></category></entry><entry><title>WHAT DOES SUCCESS LOOK LIKE</title><link href="/2020/01/what-does-success-look-like/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-01-13T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2020-01-13T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>EDIE YE</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-01-13:/2020/01/what-does-success-look-like/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The question “What makes one successful in life?” can usually be answered with a tangible good (e.g. money) or an abstract thought (e.g. power). That said, a fundamental problem to such answers is the possible controversy that can arise. The reason being is that success tends to fall …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The question “What makes one successful in life?” can usually be answered with a tangible good (e.g. money) or an abstract thought (e.g. power). That said, a fundamental problem to such answers is the possible controversy that can arise. The reason being is that success tends to fall in the hands of the beholder, meaning that there is no universal truth to success that is shared amongst everyone. The sub-questions that then follow are “How do you measure success?” or even more simply, “What is the definition of success?” The &lt;a href="https://www.dictionary.com/browse/webster-s-dictionary"&gt;Webster Dictionary&lt;/a&gt; defines
&lt;a href="https://www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary/success"&gt;success&lt;/a&gt; as “the fact of getting or achieving, wealth, respect or fame” which again, can be the definition for some people or the majority even, but that definition is not universal. At different points in life, the definitions and or measurements of success change. For this reason, I will write more on what intrinsic traits a successful person possesses rather than trying to draw a picture of a successful person. Although I am by no means at the stage where I can label myself as successful per se, I will delve into this topic further by sharing some of my successful experiences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the earliest memories I have of my childhood takes me back to my first days or week of preschool. I, for whatever reason, was riddled with separation anxiety from my grandpa, who at the time, was not only my guardian, but my best friend as well. It was honestly a strange concept because I remembered each child that was dropped off by a family member or guardian, and their ability to immediately interact with children and toys around them after being dropped off. Anyways, my grandpa had to remain with me while I interacted with the other kids and I remember every time he made a futile attempt to sneak away, I would cry almost immediately. The whole process of me getting comfortable with everyone took around a week and, if I remember correctly, it wasn’t until that period was over that I was able to be without the presence of my grandpa. While this may be seen as an embarrassment to others or a questionable experience even, it was my first memorable taste of victory and success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;BE PATIENT&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In hindsight, there are a number of general accomplishments that happen in our lives whether we realize this or not, not limited to but including learning to walk, to read, or even to use the toilet. While these events have transpired quite a period of time ago, it is important to recognize the amount of time and energy that went into being successful with these tasks. This brings me to the first attribute of being successful—learning to &lt;strong&gt;be patient.&lt;/strong&gt; As cliche as it sounds, success is not something that happens over night. I say this because as a child, I believe that one of the traits many of us shared was not giving up easily and having the courage to attempt new activities, hence being able to effectively learn to verbally communicate, socially interact with others, etc. Speaking entirely for myself, I realized as I grew older, I saw a shift in how much quicker I would need to see results before deeming activities as worth the time. I saw while I was learning to be more patient with others, how impatient I was when it came to myself. The reason behind this is as I grew older, I learned more about myself. When I say learning more about myself, I mean understanding my goals, aspirations, likes, and dislikes. I mean having expectations for myself, which I hold to the highest standard. While it is so, so important to have goals and aspirations, this is a reminder to myself and everyone to be patient with not only the people around them but with themselves as well because success will come with time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;BE RESPECTFUL&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was fifteen, I took on my first job at the &lt;a href="https://www.pne.ca/"&gt;PNE&lt;/a&gt; as a sweeper and this has been rewarding in every aspect. It was not the job duties itself that was monumental nor was there a life changing event that took my breath away. However, it taught me about the value of money (because your sweat translating to your first pay cheque is a woohoo moment), about consistency, and most importantly, about hard work. I then went on to pick up other work prior to the beginning of my software development career, including serving in a restaurant, working in retail, working in concession stands, and even working as a manager in my high school store. If you want to read more about where I interned or where I am currently working you can read more &lt;a href="edieye.ca/about"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Needless to say, I would love to go into detail about each of my work experiences, but it would stray too far from the point I am trying to establish—learning to treat everyone you meet with respect and as an opportunity to learn. &lt;strong&gt;Being respectful&lt;/strong&gt; is of great value and realizing that every person you meet can teach you something will never, ever hinder your growth. This is because the people you meet can teach you what to be and what not to be. I believe, every now and then, quite unintentionally, someone teaches you something about yourself. I say this because I remember serving at a restaurant and witnessing dishwashers being treated poorly by some servers. I remember there was a basket which was intended for the server to put their dirty dishes in. Some servers, out of laziness, would toss dishes that still had food remains into the said basket and remains or sauces would deflect back onto the dishwashers’ clothes or face, even. Of course, this was of the rarest occasions and, of course, the servers apologized but there was, without a doubt, a blatant disregard for the dishwasher. Had it been someone of a deemed, valuable position, I doubt the dishes would have been carelessly tossed into the basket. Yes, I am elucidating the impression that some people are condescending and mistreat others and yes, I am asking you to not behave in this manner because not only is it a backwards movement, but it hinders growth. It is beneficial to recognize the value of every person you meet and every experience that takes place because growth comes from reflection, and not from exuding negativity towards others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;BE CONFIDENT&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last trait I want to talk about is one I struggled with for a good period of time—&lt;strong&gt;being confident.&lt;/strong&gt; I say this to the people that don’t believe they have what it takes to take themselves to the level they aspire to be to find the courage to do so. My prior anecdote about my preschool experience is a translation for the parts of my life where I honestly felt uncomfortable being under my own skin. Truth is, you have to put yourself in uncomfortable situations because these situations will eventually become comfortable to you. For example, take a look at typing with a keyboard. At one point in our lives, we probably used two index fingers and had trouble typing a complete sentence without looking up at the screen. After finishing the sentence, being slightly smug about it, and then looking at our screen again, we probably realized that we had mistyped. &lt;em&gt;How uncomfortable.&lt;/em&gt; I understand that for some people, even getting out of bed and having basic conversation with others can be exhausting, but recognize that as long as you take baby steps to work on being comfortable with the uncomfortable, the confidence will eventually come! With that said, it is also important to recognize the difference between being arrogant and confident. As &lt;a href="https://theoffice.fandom.com/wiki/Vikram"&gt;Vikram&lt;/a&gt; would say, “confidence, it’s the food of the wise man, but the liquor of the fool.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many traits that can help lead one to success but those are the three I am trying to work on in the coming year and I know how cliche these traits are made out to be. Truth is, everything in life is cliche. The idea that you are very different from someone else is only true if you consider a &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Decision_tree"&gt;decision tree&lt;/a&gt;, where each step or decision would alter the course of life. However, these branches very often intersect and lead to a similar path. Even the idea that you think you are different is not much different than the other millions of people that have shared this thought , and with that said, I truly believe anyone can feel or be successful regardless of how many bad branches that stemmed from their tree. I have digressed again but I believe success is intrinsic and can not be answered with some social status or some physical good. Success is ultimately looking in the mirror and liking what you see.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="2020"></category><category term="pelican"></category><category term="self"></category><category term="patience"></category><category term="memory"></category><category term="success"></category><category term="life"></category><category term="confidence"></category></entry><entry><title>WHY YOU SHOULD GO ON</title><link href="/2020/01/why-you-should-go-on/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-01-09T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2020-01-09T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>EDIE YE</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-01-09:/2020/01/why-you-should-go-on/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;One of the saddest messages I received recently was that one of my childhood friends was at the tipping point of depression. I am dedicating this post wholeheartedly to you and to everyone else who feels that their world is moments from crumbling down. This is a reminder that sometimes …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;One of the saddest messages I received recently was that one of my childhood friends was at the tipping point of depression. I am dedicating this post wholeheartedly to you and to everyone else who feels that their world is moments from crumbling down. This is a reminder that sometimes, there are events that take place which we have absolutely no control over. We do have a choice though, which is either to give up or to &lt;strong&gt;keep on fighting,&lt;/strong&gt; and I hope your choice is to keep on fighting. &lt;em&gt;Every damn time.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me begin by saying I am no expert in human psychology nor do I know how to take methodical approaches with conversation to better understand victims with depression. With that in mind, these are the aspects of life that I personally think are worth living for, and in turn, the reasons you need to keep &lt;strong&gt;fighting.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;LIVE FOR FAMILY&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You need to live for your family, whether it is your parents, siblings, pets, or friends who have become family. I believe the term family goes hand in hand with home, so when I think of family, I tend to think of things that make me feel at &lt;strong&gt;home.&lt;/strong&gt; These things could be, well, anything that makes you feel at peace. It could be a thought, a place, or even a person, because home is as simple as that. It is but a feeling, a thought. Some people can argue that they have no home or that they are difficult to love, but that is silly. Look harder. Look smarter. One of the greatest gifts that humans have been blessed with is the ability to make foreign places and people their home. There must be a moment, a thought, or a memory that triggers a flux in serotonin which you can hold onto with your dear life. Personally, when I think about home, the first thought that comes to mind are my parents who immigrated to Canada and sacrificed their passions and career for me to chase mine. Every time I encounter hardships, I am reminded of how disappointed my parents would be if I decided to give up on myself, when they have yet to give up on me. The inexplicable, unconditional parental love truly has me at a loss for words, but its complexity is something I will perpetually cherish. By the way mom, if you ever stumble upon and read this, this in no way implies that I am willing to do the dishes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;LIVE FOR SUNSETS AND SUNRISES&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You need to live for sunsets and sunrises. Do I need to say more? The fleeting beauty of sunsets and sunrises never fail to take me away from my perceived troubles. There is something extremely peaceful about commodities that humans have no control over. Humans have a strange tendency to want to control things, to plan things, and I am no exception. However, when I have the opportunity to slip away from the working world and focus entirely on the elapsing beauty of the sun being swallowed away by the clouds, I am reminded again of the endless possibilities of life. It is empowering to think, when you look at the sun, that there are no apparent social hierarchies or arcane policies of monarchy. This is because the feelings that evoke and the experiences that form are completely and &lt;strong&gt;utterly yours.&lt;/strong&gt; In those moments, you need to realize that even the darkest nights will soon burn bright again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;LIVE FOR FIRST EXPERIENCES&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You need to live for first time experiences. There are so many first times and the few that quickly come to my mind are graduating from high school, graduating from college, riding a bike, driving a car, and flying in an airplane. Every time I reflect on a first time experience, I am reminded of my stomach churning with excitement. I am reminded of the flood in emotions of both nervousness and eagerness, and it never fails to leave me in anticipation for what is yet to come. Say we compare your life to a book. The chapters would be a metaphor for each new experience, the pages for the days, and the lines for the emotions you felt and or actions of that day. It is then important to recognize that you need to read every line in the book, regardless of how you currently feel about the story. Of course, you can be sad, frustrated, or angry even but please know that a new chapter will eventually begin and the only way to know what the upcoming chapters entail is to &lt;strong&gt;keep reading.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;LIVE FOR YOURSELF&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You need to live for yourself. Live for the good. Live for the small moments that take your breath away. Live for the small moments that you have with yourself. Live because that is what it means to be alive. Live for yourself because you &lt;em&gt;can.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="2020"></category><category term="self-love"></category><category term="appreciation"></category><category term="family"></category><category term="first-experience"></category></entry><entry><title>WHY I STARTED WRITING</title><link href="/2019/12/why-i-started-writing/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-12-02T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2019-12-02T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>EDIE YE</name></author><id>tag:None,2019-12-02:/2019/12/why-i-started-writing/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;When asked why I decided to write, my knee jerk response would be why not? However, the analytical side of me wants to explore the not-so-bright part of my brain that is actively encouraging me to document part of my, very much, mundane life.  For the people reading that don …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;When asked why I decided to write, my knee jerk response would be why not? However, the analytical side of me wants to explore the not-so-bright part of my brain that is actively encouraging me to document part of my, very much, mundane life.  For the people reading that don’t know me very well or just happened to stumble on this page, I want to apologize in advance for the plethora of &lt;a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt0386676/"&gt;The Office&lt;/a&gt; references which is what I am fundamentally built on, as one of my friends would put it. To add to this, the focus of my posts are not for motivation, so if you are reading this with the intent of finding some sort of light to drive you or the means to fill an existing void, then you are probably looking in the wrong place. With that in mind, hopefully, you do find my experiences insightful and worth the read. My posts will largely be personal and I hope to share all my experiences, for regardless of whether they  were blessings or valuable experiences that did not immediately present themselves, they helped to shape me as an individual. Lastly, I want my blog to act as an unconfined space on the Internet where I can freely write about, well, anything that comes to mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us start with a brief biography about myself; I am a Bachelors of Science graduate from the University of British Columbia with a focus in computer science and am based in Vancouver, Canada. I am an avid hiker during the summer and watch The Office religiously, hence the occasional references. Another point that I can share about myself is that I was fortunate enough to be able to find an area of study (i.e. computer science) which I thoroughly enjoy. That being said, it honestly wasn’t a clear path to begin with and even when I decided with computer science, there were quite a few hurdles to overcome. I will probably expand further on the ins and outs of the reasons I decided to partake in my software development journey in a post or a portion of a post to come.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The result of me pursuing computer science has resulted in me to take on a more structured approach to thinking about problems and while this has been rewarding in many aspects, one of the spaces I no longer found myself in was creative writing. This is not to say that programming lacks a creative side, as there are multiple solutions to a single problem and many developers tackle problems in a different manner. However, I missed the freedom of having my mind sporadically run off on a tangent. In other words, I wasn’t able to find the type of freedom in my everyday activities that creative writing allows for. While structured approaches and logic are great for reasoning and explaining problems as one can map out points from A to B and from B to C, I believe there is a creative outlet in writing that can’t be tapped from logic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another reason I decided to write after much consideration is that I wanted to leave a digital footprint that I can look back on when feeling nostalgic. One of the cruel realities of life is not being wired to remember all the highlights of our lives. While technologies such as the camera or video recorder have given us the ability to capture these moments in real time, there are periods in our lives where it would be inappropriate to use such technologies (e.g. movie theater). Moreover, I believe that even when the moments are appropriate to capture through technology, writing can simply act as an extension to these captured memories. Writing allows for the time to collect thoughts and emotions to reflect on specific moments in time. Lastly, I once was a firm believer in not capturing moments with photos or videos as I didn’t think you were seizing the moment with the presence of your phone. Nonetheless, after realizing that our brains are not structured to remember every immaculate detail of an experience, it makes logical sense to capture at least part of the experience prior to putting the technologies away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea of primal instinct suggests that humans, as a species, are motivated by self-preservation and survival which complies with &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Darwinism"&gt;Darwin’s Theory of Evolution&lt;/a&gt;. The reason I bring this up is that I believe that it is an instinct to want to protect yourself, an instinct to want to be cherished, and an instinct to want to compete. To accentuate my point, when we look at &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural_selection"&gt;natural selection&lt;/a&gt;, we can see there are many animals with cannibalistic tendencies and this can be seen as basic competition. Now, fortunately for us, the majority of animals and humans in contemporary society have evolved to not compete to this extent as somewhere along the way, we learned about compassion. Having said all that, I do believe that humans, when pushed to extremes, can and will release their buried anger in forms of hostility. This is why we have hobbies, loved ones, and other forms of stress relievers to suppress this innate behavior. I know I did run off on a tangent there, but I guess what I want to say is one of the reasons for the creation of this blog is to allow my mind to wander and release the stresses that come with ordinary, everyday living. I hope that answers why I am writing and if it still doesn’t, my response would again be, why not?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you for reading about a very ordinary post from my very ordinary life. Feel free to leave suggestions for what topics you want me to cover or things I could improve on as any constructive feedback would be greatly appreciated. Hopefully this post urges you to find a passion or hobby that takes away the stresses of everyday living and helps you to realize that it is quite alright to be ordinary. As &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pam_Beesly"&gt;Pam&lt;/a&gt; would say, “there’s a lot of beauty in ordinary things. Isn’t that the point?”&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="2019"></category><category term="pelican"></category><category term="publishing"></category><category term="self"></category><category term="blog"></category></entry></feed>