<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Just For Fun - cosmos</title><link href="/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="/feeds/cosmos.tag.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>/</id><updated>2020-01-17T00:00:00-08:00</updated><entry><title>WHAT IS THE MEANING OF LIFE</title><link href="/2020/01/what-is-the-meaning-of-life/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-01-17T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2020-01-17T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>EDIE YE</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-01-17:/2020/01/what-is-the-meaning-of-life/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have compiled a list of the two types of questions that are humanly impossible to answer, with one being &lt;a href="https://www.cut-the-knot.org/WhatIs/WhatIsAnalyticGeometry.shtml"&gt;analytic geometry&lt;/a&gt; in the third dimension (haha math is tough) and the other being questions of this form. That said, since you are already here, let me answer the impossible …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have compiled a list of the two types of questions that are humanly impossible to answer, with one being &lt;a href="https://www.cut-the-knot.org/WhatIs/WhatIsAnalyticGeometry.shtml"&gt;analytic geometry&lt;/a&gt; in the third dimension (haha math is tough) and the other being questions of this form. That said, since you are already here, let me answer the impossible to the best of my ability. Let me first ask you a few sub-questions—&lt;strong&gt;what&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;where&lt;/strong&gt; are we in the &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cosmos"&gt;cosmos&lt;/a&gt;?, &lt;strong&gt;why&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;how&lt;/strong&gt; does gravity prevent us from spinning off into space?, &lt;strong&gt;who&lt;/strong&gt; created the first form of life?, &lt;strong&gt;if&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;when&lt;/strong&gt; will time one day pass in reverse?, and &lt;strong&gt;what&lt;/strong&gt; are the ultimate limits to humans can know?
These questions, similar to the meaning of life, are difficult to answer yet have beauty because they are of the unknown. That said, maybe the meaning of life is simply, here and now. Maybe the journey—the struggling, the frustration, the hard work, and the tears themselves is the point. Maybe don't be so focused on searching for the meaning of life when the meaning of life is to give it meaning. Maybe, just maybe, the point is to avoid controlling things and just, well, &lt;em&gt;live&lt;/em&gt;. As &lt;a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt1065073/characters/nm3878243"&gt;Nicole&lt;/a&gt; would say, “You know how everyone’s always saying seize the moment? I don’t know, I’m kinda thinking its the other way around. You know, like the moment seizes us.”&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="2020"></category><category term="pelican"></category><category term="life"></category><category term="meaning"></category><category term="cosmos"></category><category term="gravity"></category><category term="moment"></category></entry></feed>