<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Just For Fun - life</title><link href="/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="/feeds/life.tag.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>/</id><updated>2020-04-04T00:00:00-07:00</updated><entry><title>BOJACK HORSEMAN</title><link href="/2020/04/bojack-horseman/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-04-04T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-04-04T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>EDIE YE</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-04-04:/2020/04/bojack-horseman/</id><summary type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Usually when people ask how I’m doing, the real answer is I’m doing shitty, but I can’t say I’m doing shitty, because I don’t even have a good reason to be doing shitty. So if I say, “I’m doing shitty” then they say, “why …&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Usually when people ask how I’m doing, the real answer is I’m doing shitty, but I can’t say I’m doing shitty, because I don’t even have a good reason to be doing shitty. So if I say, “I’m doing shitty” then they say, “why? what’s wrong?” And I have to be like, “ I don’t know, all of it?” So instead, when people ask me how I’m doing, I usually say, “I am doing so great.”- BoJack  &lt;a href="https://www.pinterest.pt/pin/720364902878836038/"&gt;img&lt;/a&gt; (Season 5, Episode 6)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are unfamiliar with &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/BoJack_Horseman"&gt;BoJack Horseman&lt;/a&gt;, it is a dark, animated comedy encompassing a horse named BoJack (I know you couldn't tell from the title). He was previously a major celebrity – a direct result of his role in the 1990s sitcom Horsin' Around – and even more previously, a victim of childhood abuse. The show is brilliant for its capture of real-life obstacles (i.e. depression, trauma, self-destructive behavior, addiction, sexuality, and racism) that many humans face as we traverse through this thing called life. I applaud the show for its role on the destigmatization of mental health and rather than write a summary of the story, largely because I believe you should go watch it yourself if you haven't already, I have decided to use the allotted space (i.e. this site) to share my favorite quotes from the six seasons. As there will be spoilers, I have divided the quotes into sections by season and if you have a favorite quote that I missed, feel free to &lt;a href="mailto:edieye_blog@hotmail.com"&gt;email&lt;/a&gt; me. I have also attached, for those available, an image or video of the dialogue between the characters to jog your memory of its relevance in the story. I take no credit for any of the images or videos used – I am solely compiling this information for myself and other fans of the show.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;TABLE OF CONTENTS &lt;a name="BACK"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="#ONE"&gt;SEASON 1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="#TWO"&gt;SEASON 2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="#THREE"&gt;SEASON 3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="#FOUR"&gt;SEASON 4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="#FIVE"&gt;SEASON 5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="#SIX"&gt;SEASON 6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;SEASON 1 &lt;a name="ONE"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diane : "You're responsible for your own happiness, you know?" &lt;br&gt;
BoJack : “God, that’s depressing.” &lt;a href="https://pin.it/5giWmZU"&gt;img&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2WELLE2nptU"&gt;vid&lt;/a&gt; (Episode 1)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BoJack : "Life is just one long hard kick in the urethra." &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kGT7DGOsOV8"&gt;vid&lt;/a&gt; (Episode 1)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BoJack : “You know what the problem is with everybody? They all just want to hear what they already believe. No one ever wants to hear the truth.” &lt;a href="https://pin.it/2bU51iE"&gt;img&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br&gt;
Diane : "I want to hear the truth. I don't know if you want to tell it though." (Episode 2)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BoJack : "Maybe because you're skinny, and maybe because you're pretty, you're used to getting away with things. But I want you to know that your actions have an effect on others, and I hate you, and you are a horrible person, and not understanding that you're a horrible person does not make you less of a horrible person." &lt;a href="https://yarn.co/yarn-clip/39c6f12f-f16e-4913-b7c7-8d786e8071c9"&gt;vid&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Pam : "You think I'm pretty?" (Episode 2)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BoJack : "People usually don't want to hang out with me after rehab. I'm really more of a before rehab friend." (Episode 3)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BoJack : "The most important thing is you got to give the people what they want. Even if it kills you, even if it empties you out until there's nothing left to empty. No matter what happens, no matter how much it hurts, you don't stop dancing, and you don't stop smiling, and you give those people what they want." (Episode 3)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sarah Lynn's Mother : "Honey, college is for ugly people who can't tap-dance." &lt;a href="https://getyarn.io/yarn-clip/011f144c-3d1e-48d4-8e5a-21d1a5fe9aa6"&gt;vid&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br&gt;
Sarah Lynn : "I want to be an architect." &lt;br&gt;
Sarah Lynn's Mother : "Sweetheart, Mommy didn't do what Mommy did to that star search producer so that you could be an architect." (Episode 3)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wayne : "You can live your happy Zelda life in this happy Zelda town and pretend you're a happy Zelda, but I know you, and this isn't you.&lt;br&gt;
Wayne : People don't change, Diane, not really. Mr. Peanutbutter's a Zelda. He's happy and he's carefree and he's loving, but you and me, we're Zoes... We're Zoes, Diane. &lt;a href="https://horseman-bojack.tumblr.com/image/159878291244"&gt;img&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Wayne : We're cynical and we're sad and we're mean. There's a darkness inside you, and you can bury it deep in burritos as big as your head, but someday soon, that darkness is gonna come out, and when it does, I want you to call me." (Episode 4)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BoJack : "What's great about Los Angeles is nobody cares where you're from or who you are. It's a superficial town where you can worry about stupid shit like keeping your pool clean, and what artisanal nuts to put on your salad." (Episode 5)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BoJack : "That's not true. I can express feelings." &lt;br&gt;
BoJack : "Nothing on the outside. Nothing on the inside." &lt;a href="https://www.pinterest.ca/pin/518265869593459040/"&gt;img&lt;/a&gt; (Episode 6)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Herb : "You know what your problem is? You want to think of yourself as the good guy. Well, I know you better than anyone, and I can tell you that you're not. In fact, you'd probably sleep a lot better at night if you just admit to yourself that you're a selfish, goddamn coward who takes whatever he want, and doesn't give a shit about who he hurts! That's you!" (Episode 8)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BoJack : "Um, I-I guess my question is do you... do you think it's too late for me?" &lt;br&gt;
Diane : "What?" &lt;br&gt;
BoJack : "I mean a-a-a-a-a-a-am I just doomed to be the person that I am? Th-The person in that book? I mean i-it's not too late for me, is it? It's not too late? Diane, I need you to tell me it's not too late." &lt;br&gt;
Diane : "BoJack, I..." &lt;br&gt;
BoJack : "I-I-I-I need you to tell me that I'm a good person. I know that I can be selfish and narcissistic and self-destructive, but underneath all that, deep down, I'm a good person, and I need you to tell me that I'm good. Diane? Tell me, please, Diane. Tell me that I'm good." &lt;a href="https://www.pinterest.ca/pin/554787247825806112/"&gt;img&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=45a1NTArG-g"&gt;vid&lt;/a&gt; (Episode 11)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diane : "BoJack, when people find out that someone like you, who seems larger than life, is actually just as wounded and vulnerable as they are, it makes them feel less lonely." (Episode 11)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BoJack : "This is my last chance to make people love me again. If this goes out, everybody's gonna see the real me. Now, I spend a lot of time with the real me, and believe me, nobody's gonna love that guy." (Episode 11)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Todd : "As you know, I was hurt. But then I realised, that's just how you are. You know, and maybe I just need to stop expecting you to be a good person, so that way I won't get hurt when you're not." (Episode 11)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diane : "It's never too late to be the person you want to be. You need to choose the life you want." &lt;a href="https://pin.it/5nvxmxw"&gt;img&lt;/a&gt; (Episode 11)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diane : "Well, That's the problem with life, right? Either you know what you want, and then you don't get what you want. Or you get what you want, and then you don't know what you want." (Episode 12)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diane : "That's the thing - I don't think I believe in deep down. I kind of think all you are is just the things that you do." &lt;a href="https://weheartit.com/entry/320307627"&gt;img&lt;/a&gt; (Episode 12)
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="#BACK"&gt;BACK TO TABLE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;SEASON 2 &lt;a name="TWO"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beatrice Horseman : "You better grow up to be something great, to make up for all the damage you've done." (Episode 1)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beatrice Horseman : "I just wanted to tell you... I know. I know you wanna be happy, but you won't be, and... I'm sorry. It's not just you, you know. Your father and I, we, well... You come by it, honestly, the ugliness inside you. I know you you were born broken, that's your birthright. And now you can fill your life with projects. Your books and your movies and your little girlfriends but it won't make you whole. You're BoJack. There's no cure for that." &lt;a href="https://pin.it/3Lfyrxw"&gt;img&lt;/a&gt; (Episode 1)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Princess Carolyn : "You know a lot of people go their whole lives and they never give a damn. But Herb, he gave those beavers a dam." (Episode 3)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BoJack : "Yea, I'm calling this road-trip a double-O seven, because we are going to bond." (Episode 5)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mr.Peanutbutter : "Team players wanted"? Oh, I'm such a good team player, I make all the other team players look like garbage." (Episode 6)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mr. Peanutbutter : "All I ever wanted was to be your friend. And you treat me like a big joke. You think I don't notice? Why don't you like me?" &lt;br&gt;
BoJack : "Mr. Peanutbutter..."
Mr. Peanutbutter : "No, tell me." &lt;br&gt;
BoJack : "Because... "I'm jealous." &lt;br&gt;
Mr. Peanutbutter : "Oh. Of what? Diane?" &lt;br&gt;
BoJack : "No. Of everything. Everything comes so easy for you." &lt;br&gt;
Mr. Peanutbutter : "Oh, and it doesn't for you? You're a millionaire movie star with a girlfriend who loves you, acting in your dream movie. What more do you want? What else could the universe possible owe you?" &lt;br&gt;
BoJack : "I want... to feel good about myself. The way you do. And I don't know how. I don't know if I can." &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zIeGfsTbofM"&gt;vid&lt;/a&gt; (Episode 8)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wanda Pierce : "What happened, BoJack?" &lt;br&gt;
BoJack : "Same thing that always happens. You didn't know me and then you fell in love with me. And now you know me." &lt;br&gt;
Wanda Pierce : "When you look at the world through rose-colored glasses, all the red flags just look like flags." &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=huPtWcb982o"&gt;vid&lt;/a&gt; (Episode 10)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Charlotte : “I don't care where you go, BoJack, but I can't have you around here, you make me too sad." (Episode 11)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BoJack : "I don't understand how people... live. It's amazing to me that people wake up every morning and say: 'Yeah, another day, let's do it.' How do people do it? I don't know how." &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4m3MrfnCecg"&gt;vid&lt;/a&gt; (Episode 11)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rutabaga Rabitowitz : "Can you really afford to be picky? What? I'm just saying, what, you think you're gonna find some perfect unattached guy who's gonna love you like I do? Who's gonna make you laugh and feel good about yourself? This is it, Carolyn, this is what you get. If you're holding out for something better, well, I hate to break it to you, but you're gonna be alone for a long time." (Episode 11)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BoJack : "Ow, crap. I hate this. Running is terrible, everything is the worst." &lt;br&gt;
BoJack : "Oh my God, oh my God." &lt;br&gt;
Jogging baboon : “It gets easier. Every day it gets a little easier. But you gotta do it every day —that’s the hard part. But it does get easier." &lt;a href="https ://www.youtube.com/watch?v=R2_Mn-qRKjA"&gt;vid&lt;/a&gt; (Episode 12)
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="#BACK"&gt;BACK TO TABLE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;SEASON 3 &lt;a name="THREE"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BoJack : "How do you make something right when you’ve made it so wrong you can never go back." &lt;br&gt;
Reporter : "I think you have to keep moving forward?" &lt;br&gt;
BoJack : "All my life that’s all I’ve ever done. What’s it gotten me?" (Episode 1)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diane : "It’s not about being happy, that is the thing. I’m just trying to get through each day. I can’t keep asking myself 'Am I happy?' It just makes me more miserable. I don’t know If I believe in it, real lasting happiness, All those perky, well-adjusted people you see in movies and TV shows ? I don’t think they exist." (Episode 3)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BoJack : "No one’s happy all the time, you have to focus on the small things." (Episode 3)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diane : "Everyone was worried about you, you know. You can’t just disappear. You really hurt a lot of people." &lt;br&gt;
Cuddlywhiskers : "Sometimes you need to take responsibility for you own happiness." &lt;br&gt;
Diane : "You don't think that's a little selfish?" &lt;br&gt;
Cuddlywhiskers : "I don’t know what to tell you. I’m happy for the first time in my life and I’m not gonna feel bad about it. It takes a long time to realize how truly miserable you are and even longer to see it doesn’t have to be that way. Only after you give up everything can you begin to find a way to be happy." &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0FOtyg7lnrE"&gt;vid&lt;/a&gt; (Episode 3)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BoJack : "Kelsey, in this terrifying world, all we have are the connections we make. I'm sorry I got you fired. I'm sorry I never called you after." (Episode 4)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BoJack : "Taneisha, nobody completes anybody. That's not a real thing! If you're lucky enough to find someone you can halfway tolerate, you sink your nails in and you don't let go, no matter what." &lt;br&gt;
Taneisha : "So what? I should just... settle?" &lt;br&gt;
BoJack : "Yes! Thank you, exactly: settle! Because, otherwise, you're just gonna get older and harder and more alone. And you're gonna do everything you can to fill that hole- with friends and your career and meaningless sex, but the hole... doesn't get filled. And one day you're going to look around and you're going to realize that everybody loves you... but nobody likes you. And that is the loneliest feeling in the world." &lt;a href="https://www.pinterest.ca/pin/686517536929968421/"&gt;img&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1zszD_-xM2w"&gt;vid&lt;/a&gt; (Episode 5)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diane : "... and sometimes I think I know myself, but maybe that's a trap. Because maybe I am Cool Sexy Diane or Really in Touch with Her Feelings Diane or possibly other Dianes we don't even know about yet. The point is, I am all of the Dianes." (Episode 5)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The closer : "When you do bad things, you have something you can point to when people eventually leave you. It’s not you, you tell yourself. It’s that bad thing you did. Do you often keep people at arm’s length? Are you afraid of being known and knowing others?" (Episode 7)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BoJack : "Yeah, she was right. It’s so sad when you see someone as they really are, it ruins them." &lt;a href="https://weheartit.com/entry/326961336"&gt;img&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://tv.getyarn.io/yarn-clip/8a262b07-7f39-4327-98c0-c926be043a58"&gt;vid&lt;/a&gt; (Episode 7)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The closer : "No, because that’s just theater. It allows you to think you’re in control but the whole idea of control is a myth. The universe is a wild beast. You can’t tame it. All you can do is try to live inside it." (Episode 7)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mr Peanutbutter : "It's so cruel to let people love you. All you're doing is promising you'll one day break their hearts." &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=40figWEmK38"&gt;vid&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.pinterest.ca/pin/355995545539724391/"&gt;img&lt;/a&gt; (Episode 8)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BoJack : "You like being there to rescue me. Because it makes you feel good about yourself Princess Carolyn. Please, you’re such a self-pitying masochist, I could say ten nice things and one mean thing and you would only hear the one mean thing." (Episode 9)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BoJack : "You know that I don’t do the whole love thing. Either you end up hurting someone or they hurt you. So what’s the point?" (Episode 9)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Princess Carolyn : "Your heart is tender, so you protect it from people, but sometimes you open up a wall and it’s incredible. You’re doing the best you can considering your asshole parents." (Episode 9)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BoJack : "Just 'cause you're good at something doesn't mean you have to do it. I'm good at driving sober, but I don't relish the opportunity."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ana : "BoJack, don’t do this. Don’t fetishize your own sadness." (Episode 10)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BoJack : "Todd, I'm sorry, alright? I screwed up, I- I know I screwed up, I—" &lt;br&gt;
Todd : "Oh great, of course! Here it comes! You can't keep doing this! You can't keep doing shitty things and then feel bad about yourself like that makes it okay! You need to be better!" &lt;br&gt;
BoJack : "I know, and I'm sorry, okay? I was drunk and there was all this pressure with the Oscar campaign, but now that it's over, I- I- I—" &lt;br&gt;
Todd : "No! No, BoJack, just stop. You are all the things that are wrong with you. It’s not the alcohol or the drugs or any of the shitty things that happened to you in your career or when you were a kid. It’s you. Alright, it’s you. Fuck man, what else is there to say." &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ohoLzH9EQzg"&gt;vid&lt;/a&gt; (Episode 10)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Random bird : "And I realized people don’t change because they want to change. They change because they have to change." (Episode 11)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sara-Lynn : "Hey, we have all done shitty stuff before. Most of us aren’t as proud of it as you seem to be." (Episode 11)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sarah Lynn : [her final words] "I want to be an architect." (Episode 11)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BoJack : "See, Sarah Lynn? We're not doomed. In the grand scheme of things, we're just tiny specks that will one day be forgotten. So it doesn't matter what we did in the past, or how we'll be remembered. The only thing that matters is right now. This moment. This one spectacular moment we are sharing together. Right, Sarah Lynn? Sarah Lynn? Sarah Lynn?" &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=o6ml5FdnXiA"&gt;vid&lt;/a&gt; (Episode 11)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ana : "There are going to be times when you’ll see someone in trouble. You’re going to want to rush in there and do whatever you can to save them, but you have to stop yourself. Because there are some people you can’t save. Cause those people will thrash and struggle and try to take you down with them." (Episode 11)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BoJack : "Liquor before beer." &lt;br&gt;
BoJack : "Never fear." &lt;br&gt;
BoJack : "Don't do heroin." (Episode 11)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BoJack : "I don’t know how to be Diane. It doesn’t get better and it doesn’t get easier. I can’t keep lying to myself thinking I’m gonna change, I’m poison. I come from poison and I have poison inside me and I destroy everything I touch. That’s my legacy. I have nothing to show for the live I have lived. And I have nobody in my life who’s better off for having known me." &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fVFROLk7ZBU"&gt;vid&lt;/a&gt; (Episode 12)
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="#BACK"&gt;BACK TO TABLE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;SEASON 4 &lt;a name="FOUR"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eddie : "Where are you going?" &lt;br&gt;
BoJack : "Home." (Episode 2)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hollyhock : "Ever since I was a baby, people have always said that I kind of look like BoJack." &lt;br&gt;
Todd : "Oh my god! That is a terrible thing to say to a baby!" (Episode 3)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BoJack : "But now I can feel her getting attached, and I just know I'm gonna BoJack things up." &lt;br&gt;
Mr. Peanutbutter : "BoJack things up? You mean, show up somewhere and be the life of the party? Then share a laugh with your good friend, Mr. Peanutbutter?" &lt;br&gt;
BoJack : "No, obviously I meant screw everything up until she hates me. I don't think I can take that. Maybe this time, don't do the thing that makes her hate you. I don't want to, but every time she looks at me with those big innocent eyes, all I can think about is every shitty thing I've ever done, and I think, 'I don't deserve that kind of love'." (Episode 6)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BoJack : "You're a piece of shit, but at least I know I'm a piece of shit, that makes me better than those other pieces of shit who don't know they're pieces of shit." (Episode 6)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BoJack : "Hollyhock, I'm glad you're here. If I'm shitty, that's just because I'm shitty, and you're allowed to be mad at me. But you need to know that whatever I do, it's not your fault." &lt;br&gt;
Hollyhock : "I know. I mean, I know, but I don't always know, you know? Like sometimes I have this tiny voice in the back of my head that goes like, 'Hey, everyone hates you, and they're not wrong to feel that way.'" &lt;br&gt;
BoJack : "I know what you mean." &lt;br&gt;
Hollyhock : "That voice... the one that tells you you're worthless and stupid and ugly?" &lt;br&gt;
BoJack : "Yeah?" &lt;br&gt;
Hollyhock  : "It goes away, right? It's just like, a dumb teenage girl thing, but then it goes away?" &lt;br&gt;
BoJack : "Yeah." &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1ZGmmvgIMNk"&gt;vid&lt;/a&gt; (Episode 6)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BoJack : "You can be mad at me or you can get drunk with me, but you can't do both." &lt;br&gt;
Diane : "Watch me." (Episode 7)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jessica Biel : "The rule of man is over, now begins the rule of fire! I will no longer be shackled by the civilized society of the above ground. This is Underground and the only law here is flame. The fire wants not for justice, the fire wants not for reason, the fire desires only to be fed! Feed the fire!" (Episode 7)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Princess Carolyn : "Sometimes life is like the second season of Friday Night Lights. You have to push through and hope there's better stuff ahead." (Episode 7)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BoJack : "Okay, okay. Here's the secret to being happy." &lt;br&gt;
Diane : "Oh, I can't wait to hear this." &lt;br&gt;
BoJack : "Just pretend you are happy, and eventually you'll forget you're pretending." (Episode 7)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Princess Carolyn : "Hey, you know what I do when I have really, bad, awful, terrible day?" &lt;br&gt;
BoJack : "What?" &lt;br&gt;
Princess Carolyn : "I imagine my great, great, great granddaughter in the future talking to her class about me, she's poised and funny and tells people about me and how everything's worked out in the end, and when I think about that I think about how everything's going to work out because how else could she tell people?" &lt;br&gt;
BoJack : "But it's... fake." &lt;br&gt;
Princess Carolyn : "Yeah well... it makes me feel better." (Episode 9)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Todd : "Call me 4 out of 5 dentists, 'cause I agree!" (Episode 12)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Todd : "The woods are dark and scary, but the only way out is through!" &lt;a href="https://i.imgur.com/vk3C0z1.jpg"&gt;img&lt;/a&gt; (Episode 12)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diane : "You know, sometimes I feel like our marriage is like a Magic Eye poster." &lt;br&gt;
Mr. Peanutbutter : "I love those things." &lt;br&gt;
Diane : "I know. And it's messy. and at first glance, it doesn't seem to make any sense. And it's hard to figure out. But sometimes, if you squint at it just right, everything lines up, and it's the most perfect... beautiful, amazing thing." &lt;br&gt;
Mr. Peanutbutter : "Yeah. I know what you mean." &lt;br&gt;
Diane : "But..." &lt;br&gt;
Diane : "I'm so tired of squinting." &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iMFIehwHpSo"&gt;vid&lt;/a&gt; (Episode 12)
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="#BACK"&gt;BACK TO TABLE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;SEASON 5 &lt;a name="FIVE"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diane: "The real reason you go to Vietnam is because you see your accidentally soon-to-be ex-husband kiss someone else. At first you think, 'Oh, it's a fling. Whatever, they're drunk, it's a party. But then he puts his hand on the small of her back exactly the way he used to do to you. It means
I've got you, and when he did it to you, it made you feel safe.' And you realize he will never do that to you again.  And it breaks your heart, again after you heart was so broken that you thought it could never get anymore broken. You thought it was safe but it still, somehow, finds a new way to break. Because, even though you're the one who asked for this, now that you've got it, you are completely adrift with no compass, or map, or sense of where to go, or what to do. So you go to Vietnam. You think you might find community, a connection to something bigger, but.. you don't. In fact, you feel even more alone than you were before you left. But... you survive. You learn that you can survive being alone. &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1i2vgV7VSuk"&gt;vid&lt;/a&gt; (Episode 2)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BoJack : "Once again, my life has been worsened by a brush with musical theater." (Episode 3)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BoJack : "Beatrice Horseman was born in 1938, and she died in 2018, and I have no idea... what she wanted. Unless she just wanted what we all want: to be seen." (Episode 6)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BoJack : "We understood each other in a way, me and my mom and my dad. As screwed up as we all were, we did understand each other. My mother, she knew what it's like to feel your entire life like you're drowning with the exception of these moments, these very rare, brief instances, in which you suddenly remember... you can swim." &lt;br&gt;
BoJack : "But then again, mostly not. Mostly you're drowning. She understood that, too. And she recognized that I understood it. And Dad. All three of us were drowning, and we didn't know how to save each other, but there was an understanding that we were all drowning together." (Episode 6)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Butterscotch Horseman : "No, it's not her fault. She's doing the best she can, after all. It's just that, you can't depend on women. You can't depend on anyone. Sooner or later, you need to learn that no one else is gonna take care of you. That's what I learned when I had to make my own sandwich. You can't rely on other people, BoJack. It's good for you to know. And she's a good mother for teaching you that. You've got a head start on most kids. You're actually very lucky." (Episode 6)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BoJack : "I was in the hospital with her those last moments, and they were truly horrifying, full of nonsensical screams and cries, but there was this moment, this one instant of strange calm, where she looked in my direction and said, "I see you." That's the last thing she said to me. "I see you." Not a statement of judgment or disappointment, just acceptance and the simple recognition of another person in a room. "Hello, there. You are a person. And I see you." Let me tell you, it's a weird thing to feel at 54 years old, that for the first time in your life, your mother sees you. It's an odd realization that that's the thing you've been missing, the only thing you wanted all along, to be seen. And it doesn't feel like a relief, to finally be seen. It feels mean, like, "Oh, it turns out that you knew what I wanted, and you waited until the very last moment to give it to me." I was prepared for more cruelty. I was sure that she would get in one final zinger about how I let her down, and about how I was fat and stupid, and too tall to be an effective Lindy-hopper. How I was needy and a burden and an embarrassment. All that I was ready for. I was not ready for "I see you." Only my mother would be lousy enough to swipe me with a moment of connection on her way out. But maybe I'm giving her too much credit. Maybe it wasn't about connection. Maybe it was a... maybe it was an "I see you," like, "I see you." Like, "You might have the rest of the world fooled, but I know exactly who you are." That's more my mom's speed. Or maybe she just literally meant "I see you. You are an object that has entered my field of vision." She was pretty out of it at the end, so maybe it's dumb to try to attribute it to anything." (Episode 6)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Todd : "I guess we'd hang out together, like we already do, and you'd be my favorite person, like you already are. And when something good happened to me, like if I got a promotion at work, you'd be the first person I'd tell. And you'd smile and say, 'That's my boyfriend.'" (Episode 9)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gina Cazador : "You don't want that. For everything to be fine? How dreadfully boring." (Episode 11)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BoJack : "I don't understand why you're being so nice to me. After everything you know about me, and all the shit I've put you through. &lt;br&gt;
Diane : When I was in high school, I had this friend. Abby. She was my only friend and we did everything together. Until she got adopted by the cool kids, and then she turned on me, so fast. She used every secret she knew about me, every vulnerability. She made me miserable my entire sophomore year. But then that summer, when her mom got sick, like really sick, and all her cool friends were off vacationing in Martha's Vineyard, I was there for her." &lt;br&gt;
BoJack : "Why?" &lt;br&gt;
Diane : "Because I'm an idiot. And it was Abby. And I hated her, and I will never forgive her, but she needed me, and... she was my best friend, and I loved her. And now... you're here, and I hate you, but you're my best friend, and you need me." (Episode 12)
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="#BACK"&gt;BACK TO TABLE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;SEASON 6 &lt;a name="SIX"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Princess Carolyn : "We have so much in common. I don't know why we've spent so many years hating each other." &lt;br&gt;
Vanessa Gekko : "I never hated you. Do you hate me?" &lt;br&gt;
Princess Carolyn : [lying] "Uh, no." (Episode 2)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diane : "When I was a little girl, I thought that everything - all the abuse and neglect - it somehow made me special. And I decided that one day, I would write something that made little girls like me less alone... And if I can't write that book..." (Episode 10)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diane : “That means that all the damage I got isn’t ‘good damage.’ It’s just damage.” &lt;br&gt;
Diane : “I could have been happy this whole time and written books about girl detectives and been cheerful and popular had good parents… What was it all for?!” (Episode 10)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BoJack : "This place was supposed to be a fresh start for me. Rehab was supposed to be a fresh start. But no matter how many starts I get, there's always the same ending. Everything falls apart, and I end up alone." &lt;br&gt;
Princess Carolyn : "I'm still here, BoJack." &lt;br&gt;
BoJack : "Why?" &lt;br&gt;
Princess Carolyn : "I don't know. I'm a fool, I guess. And you were my first client. And one time you were drunk and you smiled at me, and I said: 'What?'' And you said: 'I just like being in a room with you. You make rooms good.'" &lt;br&gt;
BoJack : "You still do." &lt;br&gt;
Princess Carolyn : "I have loved you for 25 years, and I never loved anyone better. That kind of love, you only get it when you're young and stupid. I'm not gonna get it again. And when I tell my daughter the story of the great love of my life, I want it to have a happy ending." &lt;br&gt;
BoJack : "Is it possible you letting me go is the happy ending?" (Episode 11)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BoJack : "I’ve had a lot of what I thought were rock bottoms, only to discover another rockier bottom underneath.... Eventually, I decided to stop waiting for something to change me. I had to make the change myself." (Episode 12)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BoJack : "Less talkie and more coffee." (Episode 13)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BoJack : "See you on the other side." &lt;br&gt;
Herb Kazzaz : "Oh, BoJack... no. There is no other side. This is it." (Episode 15)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diane : "It's too late. What's done is done." &lt;br&gt;
BoJack : "No." &lt;br&gt;
Diane : "There's nothing I can do, BoJack. I'm not real. None of this is." &lt;br&gt;
BoJack : "So, what do I do now?" &lt;br&gt;
Diane : "BoJack, it doesn't matter." &lt;br&gt;
BoJack : "Well, if it doesn't matter, can I stay on the phone with you at least?" &lt;br&gt;
Diane : "Okay. &lt;br&gt;
BoJack : "How was your day? &lt;br&gt;
Diane : "Good." &lt;br&gt;
BoJack : "Yeah?" &lt;br&gt;
Diane : "Yeah. My day was good." (Episode 15)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Todd: "But isn't the point of art less what people put into it and more what people get out of it?" &lt;br&gt;
BoJack: "Is that the point of art?" &lt;br&gt;
Todd: "Maybe, or maybe art doesn't need a point. Maybe that's why it's called art." &lt;br&gt;
BoJack : "I can't tell if you're being smart or stupid." &lt;br&gt;
Todd : "Oh, I never know." &lt;br&gt;
BoJack : "I think you had it for a moment, and then you lost it." &lt;br&gt;
Todd : "Oh, well. It was nice while it lasted, right?" &lt;br&gt;
BoJack : "Sure. It was nice while it lasted." &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hN24urQktVE"&gt;vid&lt;/a&gt; (Episode 16)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diane : "No, I need to tell you... thank you... and... it's going to be okay... and... I'm sorry... and... thank you..." (Episode 16)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diane : "I wish I could have been the person you thought I was, the person who would save you." &lt;br&gt;
BoJack : "That was never your job." &lt;br&gt;
Diane : "Then why did you always make me feel like it was? I don't know, maybe it's everyone's job to save each other. I don't know. Anyway, I am glad you're alive." (Episode 16)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BoJack : "How'd you learn how to trust it? The happiness?"&lt;br&gt;
Diane : "I didn't. But I trust him." (Episode 16)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diane : "I think there are people that help you become the person that you end up being, and you can be grateful for them, even if they were never meant to be in your life forever." &lt;br&gt;
Diane : I'm glad i knew you too." &lt;br&gt;
BoJack : "Knew, huh?" &lt;br&gt;
Diane : "Mm" &lt;br&gt;
BoJack : "Hey, wouldn't it be funny if this night was the last time we ever talked to each other?" (Episode 16)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BoJack : "Life's a bitch and then you die, right?" &lt;br&gt;
 Diane : "Sometimes. Sometimes life's a bitch and then you keep living." &lt;br&gt;
BoJack : "Yeah." &lt;br&gt;
Diane : "But it's a nice night, huh?" &lt;br&gt;
BoJack : "Yeah. This is nice." &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KNpY-RrY2A4"&gt;vid&lt;/a&gt; (Episode 16)
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="#BACK"&gt;BACK TO TABLE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><category term="2020"></category><category term="BoJack"></category><category term="Horseman"></category><category term="life"></category><category term="quotes"></category></entry><entry><title>MY MOM</title><link href="/2020/03/my-mom/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-03-09T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-03-09T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>EDIE YE</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-03-09:/2020/03/my-mom/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;My mom is very powerful for a woman in her fifties. Let me rephrase that — my mom is very powerful, period. This is not because she practices &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tai_chi"&gt;Tai chi&lt;/a&gt; (despite this being how she sees it), but because of her ability to shut me up by just looking at me …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;My mom is very powerful for a woman in her fifties. Let me rephrase that — my mom is very powerful, period. This is not because she practices &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tai_chi"&gt;Tai chi&lt;/a&gt; (despite this being how she sees it), but because of her ability to shut me up by just looking at me. I don't know if the calm, infamous stare is a parenting technique or an asian parenting technique; the only certainty is that the calm stare is fueled by anger that can and will end me, if needed. The beauty, however, is in the inverse relationship between how angry she is and how calm she appears — the calmer she is, the more angry she eventually will become. It is ever so frightening simply because I love my mom an abnormal amount – more than I am willing to tell her. It probably has to do with her almost giving me up for adoption when I was younger. Just kidding. She could never. She is an incredible woman and mom despite me not being the best child growing up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the former years of elementary school, it was pretty much social suicide to display any form of affection to a person of the opposite gender, let alone your mom. This was very apparent when my mom continued to pick me up and greet me with a hug after school – even in the third grade. I mean, it was fine between kindergarten and the second grade, but by the third (come on now), I was basically as grown and as independent as I am today. Despite that day being more than a decade ago, I still remember it clearly. I remember how she beamed with joy and how her arms were wide open as she approached me, as if she was a human shield sheltering me from the cruel world that surrounded us. But nope. &lt;em&gt;Absolutely not.&lt;/em&gt; Her little boy had grown up. I ducked to elude the warm hug she tried to greet me with, smiled and said “not here, mom.” Little did I know that my actions were colder than day old oatmeal and I could still see the hurt in her face to this day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am lucky because she either doesn’t remember or she chooses not to remind me of that experience. Come to think of it, my mom is much cooler than I am. Aside from her great affection for her children and her incredible will to practice Tai Chi, she volunteers a bunch and has a good number of friends. Her jam-packed schedule and her ability to follow through with it every day is a demonstration of her tenacity and a reminder that I have yet to live up to my potential. I honestly would be lying if I said I wasn’t a bit jealous of how courageous she was, having transitioned to a foreign country with not a dollar to her name in an attempt to build a better life for her and her family. This is not to say she does not nag me constantly or pull rank on me to remind me where I stand because she does – and she does a damn good job of it. However, my relationship with my mom and our understanding of each other has gotten better over the years, but like all things, it has and will continue to have its share of struggle and hardship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;It was tough growing up.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lunch was awful. Just awful. For a good part of my elementary years, she packed leftover rice, huge portions of vegetables, and smeared bits of meat – it was garbage made with love and she had the audacity to call it &lt;em&gt;lunch.&lt;/em&gt; The vegetable to meat ratio was so embarrassing that I refuse to share that information to this day. On top of that, a good portion of my classmates had sandwiches for lunch – so you can imagine the discomfort I felt standing out, eating my &lt;em&gt;love-filled rice.&lt;/em&gt; I remember how elated I felt when I was able to convince her to start packing sandwiches for lunch. On that day, I opened my lunch box to reveal black forest ham and a single cheese slice stuck between two soggy whole-wheat pieces of bread; the bread might as well have been one-hundred percent whole-wheat because I was one-hundred percent not satisfied. I could feel my blood boil – the eight-year old me just wanted a decent lunch. I mentally prepared myself to yell at her that very night as I gobbled away at the sandwich. That said, the moment she got home from work, I sensed how tired she was and how insatiable I was being that I decided not to bring it up. When she asked me how the sandwich tasted, I told her it was great. This is the story of how I ended up eating soggy sandwiches for lunch, but it makes me happy reflecting on this story simply because the sandwiches were made with maternal love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;School was easy but those years were tough. My clothes were hand-me-downs from my older siblings and or cousins. My mom rarely ever bought new toys and gaming consoles were out of the question. It took me a long time to swallow the hard truth that my mom didn’t buy me nice things not because she didn’t love me, but simply because we couldn’t afford them. It was tough for her – she worked two jobs for a good part of my childhood to make ends meet. Everytime I think about how much she sacrificed and how much she will continue to sacrifice, I am reminded of how fortunate I am – so yes, between you and me, I love my mom. I have yet to say those three words to her though. I don’t know – it’s complicated.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="2020"></category><category term="love"></category><category term="mom"></category><category term="life"></category></entry><entry><title>THE BIGGEST LIE</title><link href="/2020/02/the-biggest-lie/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-02-17T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2020-02-17T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>EDIE YE</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-02-17:/2020/02/the-biggest-lie/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest lies I tell myself is I’ll start enjoying myself—I’ll start living—once I finish
this task or when that event happens. This and that. Wait. It’s almost as if my mind doesn’t want
me to live my life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What do I …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest lies I tell myself is I’ll start enjoying myself—I’ll start living—once I finish
this task or when that event happens. This and that. Wait. It’s almost as if my mind doesn’t want
me to live my life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What do I mean? I mean I keep trying to set myself up. I justify my struggle with an end goal. I tell myself once I finish highschool, once I graduate from university, once I find my significant other, once I start my mortgage–I’ll start living. It’s a means to an end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t want to wake up one day not having really lived my life. I don’t want to wake up one day wondering why time passed so &lt;em&gt;damn fast.&lt;/em&gt; I don’t want to be nostalgic of a life that I never even lived.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I always tell myself I know the perfect life exists–I just need to finish everything at hand. Then I’ll be happy. I tell myself the vision of an ideal life is within my grasp—I just need to skip some pages of my story. I have become so enamoured with looking ahead that I have forgotten to live for the now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to start treasuring things. I want to start treasuring every late night conversation I have, every sunset and sunrise I witness, and every opportunity I get to spend with my family and friends. Because this is it. This is my life. I better start enjoying the small moments that make me feel alive because one day I’ll be in the ground and it’ll all be over, you know?&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="2020"></category><category term="mental health"></category><category term="self"></category><category term="life"></category><category term="self love"></category></entry><entry><title>WHAT IS THE MEANING OF LIFE</title><link href="/2020/01/what-is-the-meaning-of-life/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-01-17T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2020-01-17T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>EDIE YE</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-01-17:/2020/01/what-is-the-meaning-of-life/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have compiled a list of the two types of questions that are humanly impossible to answer, with one being &lt;a href="https://www.cut-the-knot.org/WhatIs/WhatIsAnalyticGeometry.shtml"&gt;analytic geometry&lt;/a&gt; in the third dimension (haha math is tough) and the other being questions of this form. That said, since you are already here, let me answer the impossible …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have compiled a list of the two types of questions that are humanly impossible to answer, with one being &lt;a href="https://www.cut-the-knot.org/WhatIs/WhatIsAnalyticGeometry.shtml"&gt;analytic geometry&lt;/a&gt; in the third dimension (haha math is tough) and the other being questions of this form. That said, since you are already here, let me answer the impossible to the best of my ability. Let me first ask you a few sub-questions—&lt;strong&gt;what&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;where&lt;/strong&gt; are we in the &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cosmos"&gt;cosmos&lt;/a&gt;?, &lt;strong&gt;why&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;how&lt;/strong&gt; does gravity prevent us from spinning off into space?, &lt;strong&gt;who&lt;/strong&gt; created the first form of life?, &lt;strong&gt;if&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;when&lt;/strong&gt; will time one day pass in reverse?, and &lt;strong&gt;what&lt;/strong&gt; are the ultimate limits to humans can know?
These questions, similar to the meaning of life, are difficult to answer yet have beauty because they are of the unknown. That said, maybe the meaning of life is simply, here and now. Maybe the journey—the struggling, the frustration, the hard work, and the tears themselves is the point. Maybe don't be so focused on searching for the meaning of life when the meaning of life is to give it meaning. Maybe, just maybe, the point is to avoid controlling things and just, well, &lt;em&gt;live&lt;/em&gt;. As &lt;a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt1065073/characters/nm3878243"&gt;Nicole&lt;/a&gt; would say, “You know how everyone’s always saying seize the moment? I don’t know, I’m kinda thinking its the other way around. You know, like the moment seizes us.”&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="2020"></category><category term="pelican"></category><category term="life"></category><category term="meaning"></category><category term="cosmos"></category><category term="gravity"></category><category term="moment"></category></entry><entry><title>WHAT DOES SUCCESS LOOK LIKE</title><link href="/2020/01/what-does-success-look-like/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-01-13T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2020-01-13T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>EDIE YE</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-01-13:/2020/01/what-does-success-look-like/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The question “What makes one successful in life?” can usually be answered with a tangible good (e.g. money) or an abstract thought (e.g. power). That said, a fundamental problem to such answers is the possible controversy that can arise. The reason being is that success tends to fall …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The question “What makes one successful in life?” can usually be answered with a tangible good (e.g. money) or an abstract thought (e.g. power). That said, a fundamental problem to such answers is the possible controversy that can arise. The reason being is that success tends to fall in the hands of the beholder, meaning that there is no universal truth to success that is shared amongst everyone. The sub-questions that then follow are “How do you measure success?” or even more simply, “What is the definition of success?” The &lt;a href="https://www.dictionary.com/browse/webster-s-dictionary"&gt;Webster Dictionary&lt;/a&gt; defines
&lt;a href="https://www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary/success"&gt;success&lt;/a&gt; as “the fact of getting or achieving, wealth, respect or fame” which again, can be the definition for some people or the majority even, but that definition is not universal. At different points in life, the definitions and or measurements of success change. For this reason, I will write more on what intrinsic traits a successful person possesses rather than trying to draw a picture of a successful person. Although I am by no means at the stage where I can label myself as successful per se, I will delve into this topic further by sharing some of my successful experiences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the earliest memories I have of my childhood takes me back to my first days or week of preschool. I, for whatever reason, was riddled with separation anxiety from my grandpa, who at the time, was not only my guardian, but my best friend as well. It was honestly a strange concept because I remembered each child that was dropped off by a family member or guardian, and their ability to immediately interact with children and toys around them after being dropped off. Anyways, my grandpa had to remain with me while I interacted with the other kids and I remember every time he made a futile attempt to sneak away, I would cry almost immediately. The whole process of me getting comfortable with everyone took around a week and, if I remember correctly, it wasn’t until that period was over that I was able to be without the presence of my grandpa. While this may be seen as an embarrassment to others or a questionable experience even, it was my first memorable taste of victory and success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;BE PATIENT&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In hindsight, there are a number of general accomplishments that happen in our lives whether we realize this or not, not limited to but including learning to walk, to read, or even to use the toilet. While these events have transpired quite a period of time ago, it is important to recognize the amount of time and energy that went into being successful with these tasks. This brings me to the first attribute of being successful—learning to &lt;strong&gt;be patient.&lt;/strong&gt; As cliche as it sounds, success is not something that happens over night. I say this because as a child, I believe that one of the traits many of us shared was not giving up easily and having the courage to attempt new activities, hence being able to effectively learn to verbally communicate, socially interact with others, etc. Speaking entirely for myself, I realized as I grew older, I saw a shift in how much quicker I would need to see results before deeming activities as worth the time. I saw while I was learning to be more patient with others, how impatient I was when it came to myself. The reason behind this is as I grew older, I learned more about myself. When I say learning more about myself, I mean understanding my goals, aspirations, likes, and dislikes. I mean having expectations for myself, which I hold to the highest standard. While it is so, so important to have goals and aspirations, this is a reminder to myself and everyone to be patient with not only the people around them but with themselves as well because success will come with time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;BE RESPECTFUL&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was fifteen, I took on my first job at the &lt;a href="https://www.pne.ca/"&gt;PNE&lt;/a&gt; as a sweeper and this has been rewarding in every aspect. It was not the job duties itself that was monumental nor was there a life changing event that took my breath away. However, it taught me about the value of money (because your sweat translating to your first pay cheque is a woohoo moment), about consistency, and most importantly, about hard work. I then went on to pick up other work prior to the beginning of my software development career, including serving in a restaurant, working in retail, working in concession stands, and even working as a manager in my high school store. If you want to read more about where I interned or where I am currently working you can read more &lt;a href="edieye.ca/about"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Needless to say, I would love to go into detail about each of my work experiences, but it would stray too far from the point I am trying to establish—learning to treat everyone you meet with respect and as an opportunity to learn. &lt;strong&gt;Being respectful&lt;/strong&gt; is of great value and realizing that every person you meet can teach you something will never, ever hinder your growth. This is because the people you meet can teach you what to be and what not to be. I believe, every now and then, quite unintentionally, someone teaches you something about yourself. I say this because I remember serving at a restaurant and witnessing dishwashers being treated poorly by some servers. I remember there was a basket which was intended for the server to put their dirty dishes in. Some servers, out of laziness, would toss dishes that still had food remains into the said basket and remains or sauces would deflect back onto the dishwashers’ clothes or face, even. Of course, this was of the rarest occasions and, of course, the servers apologized but there was, without a doubt, a blatant disregard for the dishwasher. Had it been someone of a deemed, valuable position, I doubt the dishes would have been carelessly tossed into the basket. Yes, I am elucidating the impression that some people are condescending and mistreat others and yes, I am asking you to not behave in this manner because not only is it a backwards movement, but it hinders growth. It is beneficial to recognize the value of every person you meet and every experience that takes place because growth comes from reflection, and not from exuding negativity towards others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;BE CONFIDENT&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last trait I want to talk about is one I struggled with for a good period of time—&lt;strong&gt;being confident.&lt;/strong&gt; I say this to the people that don’t believe they have what it takes to take themselves to the level they aspire to be to find the courage to do so. My prior anecdote about my preschool experience is a translation for the parts of my life where I honestly felt uncomfortable being under my own skin. Truth is, you have to put yourself in uncomfortable situations because these situations will eventually become comfortable to you. For example, take a look at typing with a keyboard. At one point in our lives, we probably used two index fingers and had trouble typing a complete sentence without looking up at the screen. After finishing the sentence, being slightly smug about it, and then looking at our screen again, we probably realized that we had mistyped. &lt;em&gt;How uncomfortable.&lt;/em&gt; I understand that for some people, even getting out of bed and having basic conversation with others can be exhausting, but recognize that as long as you take baby steps to work on being comfortable with the uncomfortable, the confidence will eventually come! With that said, it is also important to recognize the difference between being arrogant and confident. As &lt;a href="https://theoffice.fandom.com/wiki/Vikram"&gt;Vikram&lt;/a&gt; would say, “confidence, it’s the food of the wise man, but the liquor of the fool.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many traits that can help lead one to success but those are the three I am trying to work on in the coming year and I know how cliche these traits are made out to be. Truth is, everything in life is cliche. The idea that you are very different from someone else is only true if you consider a &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Decision_tree"&gt;decision tree&lt;/a&gt;, where each step or decision would alter the course of life. However, these branches very often intersect and lead to a similar path. Even the idea that you think you are different is not much different than the other millions of people that have shared this thought , and with that said, I truly believe anyone can feel or be successful regardless of how many bad branches that stemmed from their tree. I have digressed again but I believe success is intrinsic and can not be answered with some social status or some physical good. Success is ultimately looking in the mirror and liking what you see.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="2020"></category><category term="pelican"></category><category term="self"></category><category term="patience"></category><category term="memory"></category><category term="success"></category><category term="life"></category><category term="confidence"></category></entry></feed>