<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Just For Fun - self love</title><link href="/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="/feeds/self-love.tag.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>/</id><updated>2020-02-17T00:00:00-08:00</updated><entry><title>THE BIGGEST LIE</title><link href="/2020/02/the-biggest-lie/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-02-17T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2020-02-17T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>EDIE YE</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-02-17:/2020/02/the-biggest-lie/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest lies I tell myself is I’ll start enjoying myself—I’ll start living—once I finish
this task or when that event happens. This and that. Wait. It’s almost as if my mind doesn’t want
me to live my life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What do I …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest lies I tell myself is I’ll start enjoying myself—I’ll start living—once I finish
this task or when that event happens. This and that. Wait. It’s almost as if my mind doesn’t want
me to live my life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What do I mean? I mean I keep trying to set myself up. I justify my struggle with an end goal. I tell myself once I finish highschool, once I graduate from university, once I find my significant other, once I start my mortgage–I’ll start living. It’s a means to an end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t want to wake up one day not having really lived my life. I don’t want to wake up one day wondering why time passed so &lt;em&gt;damn fast.&lt;/em&gt; I don’t want to be nostalgic of a life that I never even lived.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I always tell myself I know the perfect life exists–I just need to finish everything at hand. Then I’ll be happy. I tell myself the vision of an ideal life is within my grasp—I just need to skip some pages of my story. I have become so enamoured with looking ahead that I have forgotten to live for the now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to start treasuring things. I want to start treasuring every late night conversation I have, every sunset and sunrise I witness, and every opportunity I get to spend with my family and friends. Because this is it. This is my life. I better start enjoying the small moments that make me feel alive because one day I’ll be in the ground and it’ll all be over, you know?&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="2020"></category><category term="mental health"></category><category term="self"></category><category term="life"></category><category term="self love"></category></entry><entry><title>NINE THINGS TO DO TO FEEL BETTER ABOUT YOURSELF</title><link href="/2020/01/nine-things-to-do-to-feel-better-about-yourself/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-01-19T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2020-01-19T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>EDIE YE</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-01-19:/2020/01/nine-things-to-do-to-feel-better-about-yourself/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Lately, I have been researching about mental health and the problems that can arise from individuals with cognitive imbalances in the brain. This, in turn, made me think of what I personally do after being placed in a stressful situation. If you want to read more on why life is …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Lately, I have been researching about mental health and the problems that can arise from individuals with cognitive imbalances in the brain. This, in turn, made me think of what I personally do after being placed in a stressful situation. If you want to read more on why life is worth living, you can read more &lt;a href="https://edieye.ca/2020/01/why-you-should-go-on/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;FOCUS ON THE MOMENT&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stop—stop for a moment and try to focus entirely on a random object. For example, in front of my desk is an orange. Some questions that quickly arise are—&lt;em&gt;where did this orange come from?&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;how many hands have touched it?&lt;/em&gt;, or &lt;em&gt;was the orange fruit named after the colour?&lt;/em&gt; The answers to the questions themselves can remain a mystery but at that moment in time, I am directing my focus entirely on the orange and nothing else. As ridiculous as what you read might sound, it works simply because the orange acts as a bridge between life being complicated and life being as simple as that, an orange. Try it on something, &lt;em&gt;on anything.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;CLEAN&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clean. Clean the dishes. Clean your room and the entire house if you have to. I know, cleaning is boring and requires physical work—but think about how you will feel after you are finished. Think about how accomplished you will feel from such a simple activity. Who knows, maybe you’ll find money or an old belonging that brings back some good, old memories. If that isn’t enough, think about how a clean house will feel—an organized room, folded clothes, dust-free laptop and tables—&lt;em&gt;it’s uplifting.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;EXERCISE&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Run. Go outside of your safe space and just run as fast as you can. This will get your endorphins going which will result in happiness. Run until you are out of breath. Walk it off and repeat until you can’t run anymore. You feel yourself gasping for air? &lt;em&gt;That is what it means to be alive.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;TAKE A SHOWER&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shower. Not only is the shower a perfect place to sing your favourite songs out of tune but a place to reflect and feel sorry for yourself as well. Have a long, hot shower and cry your heart out if needed. Sit on the ground and let the hot water clean every inch of your body. Let the steam soak into your skin and just focus on breathing. That said, promise yourself that the moment you turn off the water, you will move on from whatever troubles you felt. Leave the shower with a clean slate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;WRITE&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Write on paper—with a pen—I don’t necessarily mean words. Let whatever is on your mind, whatever emotion or problem translate to the paper in front of you. Scribble furiously or draw a picture of &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Toby_Flenderson"&gt;Toby&lt;/a&gt; if you have to. Write anything and have it not make sense to anyone but &lt;strong&gt;yourself&lt;/strong&gt;. When you are done, rip the paper into tens, hundreds of pieces and watch as they fall to the floor—the paper is your enemy. Sometimes having destructive thoughts can make you feel good. Don’t carry it out for too long though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;DRINK TEA&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Boil some water and make some tea. There are so many health benefits that come with tea—I will leave this to the experts. Watch as the tea leaves disperse and change the colour of the water. Realize that watching colours change is a simple experience that we often overlook. Sit on a chair with the teacup in your hands and wait patiently for the tea to cool. Feel the warmth in your stomach as you slowly sip the tea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;BECOME THE PERSON YOU WOULD FALL IN LOVE WITH&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go outside and open doors for strangers. Smile as they walk past you. Go for a drive and let cars merge into your lane. Pay for an extra parking ticket and leave the second one in the machine. Compliment people on their clothes. Compliment them on their personality. Ask people about their day or story even. Talk to acquaintances and try not to interrupt. Become friends with them, even if there are language barriers, age gaps, or cultural differences. When you see someone struggling, act selflessly to help them. Maybe it will take the weight off of your shoulders—who knows?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;WRITE DOWN A LIST OF GOALS&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Write down a list of goals to achieve for the day or week. Start with easy tasks such as waking up, brushing your teeth, drinking water, or going for a walk. Tick them off as you finish them. Being organized in such a manner teaches you that every small task can be seen as an accomplishment, as a &lt;a href="https://edieye.ca/2020/01/what-does-success-look-like/"&gt;success&lt;/a&gt;. Not only will you feel as you are doing more than usual, which will pep your mood (woohoo), but it will teach you to take on a more structured approach to planning things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;TAKE A BREAK FROM THE INTERNET&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take a break. You can do it. Do you know how many meaningless little things you trouble yourself with? These platforms—Email, Twitter, Snapchat, Instagram, Quora, Tumblr, LinkedIn, Facebook—you can take a break from them for a few minutes. For a day even. Don’t get me wrong, these socials have changed our lives for the better but when you become so enamoured with them that you can’t take a small break for yourself, it can become tiring. &lt;em&gt;Very tiring.&lt;/em&gt; Make some time for yourself—just yourself.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="2020"></category><category term="pelican"></category><category term="mental health"></category><category term="self healing"></category><category term="self love"></category><category term="better"></category></entry><entry><title>WHY YOU SHOULD GO ON</title><link href="/2020/01/why-you-should-go-on/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-01-09T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2020-01-09T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>EDIE YE</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-01-09:/2020/01/why-you-should-go-on/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;One of the saddest messages I received recently was that one of my childhood friends was at the tipping point of depression. I am dedicating this post wholeheartedly to you and to everyone else who feels that their world is moments from crumbling down. This is a reminder that sometimes …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;One of the saddest messages I received recently was that one of my childhood friends was at the tipping point of depression. I am dedicating this post wholeheartedly to you and to everyone else who feels that their world is moments from crumbling down. This is a reminder that sometimes, there are events that take place which we have absolutely no control over. We do have a choice though, which is either to give up or to &lt;strong&gt;keep on fighting,&lt;/strong&gt; and I hope your choice is to keep on fighting. &lt;em&gt;Every damn time.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me begin by saying I am no expert in human psychology nor do I know how to take methodical approaches with conversation to better understand victims with depression. With that in mind, these are the aspects of life that I personally think are worth living for, and in turn, the reasons you need to keep &lt;strong&gt;fighting.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;LIVE FOR FAMILY&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You need to live for your family, whether it is your parents, siblings, pets, or friends who have become family. I believe the term family goes hand in hand with home, so when I think of family, I tend to think of things that make me feel at &lt;strong&gt;home.&lt;/strong&gt; These things could be, well, anything that makes you feel at peace. It could be a thought, a place, or even a person, because home is as simple as that. It is but a feeling, a thought. Some people can argue that they have no home or that they are difficult to love, but that is silly. Look harder. Look smarter. One of the greatest gifts that humans have been blessed with is the ability to make foreign places and people their home. There must be a moment, a thought, or a memory that triggers a flux in serotonin which you can hold onto with your dear life. Personally, when I think about home, the first thought that comes to mind are my parents who immigrated to Canada and sacrificed their passions and career for me to chase mine. Every time I encounter hardships, I am reminded of how disappointed my parents would be if I decided to give up on myself, when they have yet to give up on me. The inexplicable, unconditional parental love truly has me at a loss for words, but its complexity is something I will perpetually cherish. By the way mom, if you ever stumble upon and read this, this in no way implies that I am willing to do the dishes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;LIVE FOR SUNSETS AND SUNRISES&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You need to live for sunsets and sunrises. Do I need to say more? The fleeting beauty of sunsets and sunrises never fail to take me away from my perceived troubles. There is something extremely peaceful about commodities that humans have no control over. Humans have a strange tendency to want to control things, to plan things, and I am no exception. However, when I have the opportunity to slip away from the working world and focus entirely on the elapsing beauty of the sun being swallowed away by the clouds, I am reminded again of the endless possibilities of life. It is empowering to think, when you look at the sun, that there are no apparent social hierarchies or arcane policies of monarchy. This is because the feelings that evoke and the experiences that form are completely and &lt;strong&gt;utterly yours.&lt;/strong&gt; In those moments, you need to realize that even the darkest nights will soon burn bright again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;LIVE FOR FIRST EXPERIENCES&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You need to live for first time experiences. There are so many first times and the few that quickly come to my mind are graduating from high school, graduating from college, riding a bike, driving a car, and flying in an airplane. Every time I reflect on a first time experience, I am reminded of my stomach churning with excitement. I am reminded of the flood in emotions of both nervousness and eagerness, and it never fails to leave me in anticipation for what is yet to come. Say we compare your life to a book. The chapters would be a metaphor for each new experience, the pages for the days, and the lines for the emotions you felt and or actions of that day. It is then important to recognize that you need to read every line in the book, regardless of how you currently feel about the story. Of course, you can be sad, frustrated, or angry even but please know that a new chapter will eventually begin and the only way to know what the upcoming chapters entail is to &lt;strong&gt;keep reading.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;LIVE FOR YOURSELF&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You need to live for yourself. Live for the good. Live for the small moments that take your breath away. Live for the small moments that you have with yourself. Live because that is what it means to be alive. Live for yourself because you &lt;em&gt;can.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="2020"></category><category term="self-love"></category><category term="appreciation"></category><category term="family"></category><category term="first-experience"></category></entry></feed>