<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Just For Fun - time</title><link href="/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="/feeds/time.tag.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>/</id><updated>2020-06-14T00:00:00-07:00</updated><entry><title>TIME</title><link href="/2020/06/time/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-06-14T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-06-14T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>EDIE YE</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-06-14:/2020/06/time/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Time is linear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Time is linear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Time is linear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That sounds aggressive but time is linear and I keep treating it as if it's circular. What do I mean? Well, I very often &lt;em&gt;wait&lt;/em&gt; for things to be over and I very often &lt;em&gt;wait&lt;/em&gt; for things to happen because, in …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Time is linear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Time is linear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Time is linear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That sounds aggressive but time is linear and I keep treating it as if it's circular. What do I mean? Well, I very often &lt;em&gt;wait&lt;/em&gt; for things to be over and I very often &lt;em&gt;wait&lt;/em&gt; for things to happen because, in the back of my mind, I know a cycle repeats itself. But that's the problem though, because it doesn't - time doesn't repeat itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is much irony in time because we know it isn't promised yet we treat it as such. The reason could be that many of its attributes suggest a perpetual cycle. A minute is composed of sixty seconds, an hour of sixty minutes, a day of twenty-four hours, a week of seven days, and a year of fifty-two weeks. Every segment said above repeats itself and maybe that's the problem – we think we have time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below is an image where each square represents a week and each row a year. As there are ninety rows, this is your entire life if you live until ninety. Note: The image was taken from &lt;a href="https://waitbutwhy.com/2014/05/life-weeks.html"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;img alt="90-year-timeline" src="/2020/06/time/images/90-year-timeline.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This photo scares me. A lot. Suppose I crossed the boxes out as the weeks passed like a calendar – one big X for each week until the big day presents itself. Suppose I colour each box with either green or red – green for when the number of good days surpass the bad for that week, and red otherwise. In both scenarios, I am frightened because I never imagined life to have a deadline. I mean, I did, but not like this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That said, the photo gives me hope too. Because if I am to map / reduce my life to this chart, I want it to have a positive connotation. If I am to draw Xs', I want to draw each X with a smile. If I am to colour boxes, I want to have a plethora of green boxes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But if I want said results, it means I have to take control of my life. It means I have to take action instead of just dreaming. Because that's the thing – anyone can dream.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyone can dream to travel but it only happens when a ticket is booked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyone can dream to have a great body but it only happens with consistent exercise and a healthy diet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyone can dream to be wealthy but it only happens with discipline and hard work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So this post is a reminder to start now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Because those boxes are getting filled out either way.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="2020"></category><category term="life"></category><category term="time"></category></entry></feed>